In 1935, Ed Murrow began his careerwith CBS.
1935年，艾德 莫罗开始了 他在CBS的职业生涯
When World WarTwo broke out,..
二战爆发后...
..his voice brought the battle of Britain home to us..
..他的声音通过 他的系列广播“这里是伦敦”..
..through his "This Is London" radio series.
..将英国的战事呈现在我们面前
He started with us all,..
在电视业刚刚起步时
..many of us here tonight, when television was in its infancy,..
..他同我们 也就是今晚大多数来宾一道..
..with the news documentary show, "See It Now".
..创建了新闻纪实节目 “即时观察”
He threw stones at giants.
他敢于挑战权贵
Segregation, exploitation of migrant workers,..
种族歧视，剥削移民劳工..
..apartheid, J. Edgar Hoover,..
..南非种族隔离，埃德加 胡佛 （只手遮天的FBI头子）..
..not the least of which, his historical fight with Senator McCarthy.
..而最为称道的，是他同参议员麦卡锡 的历史性较量
He is the host of our enormously popular show "Person to Person"..
同时他也是广受欢迎的节目 “面对面”的主持人..
..and tonight he is here with his son, Casey,..
..今晚欢聚一堂的还有 他的儿子凯西..
..wife, Janet, and all of you who he's worked with,..
..太太珍妮特，以及 所有与他共事..
..inspired, lectured, and taught.
..并受之启发，训诫，教导的朋友们
Ladies and gentlemen,..
女士们，先生们..
..the Radio-Television News Directors' Association and Foundation welcomes..
..广播电视新闻主管协会与基金会欢迎..
..Mr. Edward R. Murrow.
..爱德华 R 莫罗先生
This might just do nobody any good.
这恐怕对任何人都没好处
At the end of this discourse a few people may accuse this reporter..
在这篇演说结束后 一些人可能会责难这个记者..
..of fouling his own comfortable nest,..
自毁长城
..and your organization may be accused of having given hospitality..
..并且主管机构会因 对异端，甚至危险言论..
..to heretical and even dangerous ideas.
..给予鼓励、支持而受到非难
But the elaborate structure of networks,..
不过，广播网的精细结构..
..advertising agencies, and sponsors will not be shaken or altered.
..广告商和赞助商 都不会被动摇或改变
It is my desire, if not my duty, to try to talk to you journeymen..
或许并非我的职责，可出于我的愿望 试图坦白地告知你们..
..with some candor about what is happening to radio and television.
..广播和电视业正发生着什么
And if what I say is responsible,..
如果要为我所说的负责..
..I alone am responsible for the saying of it.
..那么我一人来承担责任
Our history will be what we make of it.
我们的历史将由我们来构造
And if there are any historians about 50 or 100 years from now,..
在未来的50或100年 史学家们将找到…
..and there should be preserved..
..三大电视网已保存的
..the kinescopes of one week of all three networks,..
..的一些记录画面…
..they will there find recorded in black and white, and in color,..
..他们将会发现 这黑白或彩色的画面
..evidence of decadence, escapism,..
..折射出我们对现实世界的…
..and insulation from the realities of the world in which we live.
..堕落、逃避以及置若罔闻
We are currently wealthy, fat, comfortable, and complacent.
现在的我们富有，臃肿 安逸并且自满
We have a built-in allergy to unpleasant or disturbing information.
我们对令人不快或烦扰的事物 具有一种固有的抵触
Our mass media reflect this.
我们的大众传媒体现了这一点
But unless we get up off our fat surpluses..
可除非我们立刻从 这种自满中警醒
..and recognize that television in the main..
..并认识到 我们的电视业大体上..
..is being used to distract, delude, amuse, and insulate us,..
..正被用作来分化，蛊惑 消遣和隔离我们
..then television and those who finance it,..
..那么当等到电视业 和其投资人..
..those who look at it and those who work at it..
..观众以及从业人士..
..may see a totally different picture too late.
..看到截然不同的结果 就已经太晚了
Millie! Just the person I wanted to see! Come here!
米莉！正找你呢！过来！
This goes at the top of the Roy Campanella piece.
这篇素材是罗伊 卡帕拉报道 最重要的一部分
Yes! Give me a half an hour.
好的！给我半小时！
I may need it a little quicker than that!
可我要你再快些！
- Can I get some coffee first? - Come on! Get me some coffee!
- 让我先喝杯咖啡好吗？ - 赶紧！替我也拿一杯！
Morning, Johnny!
早上好，约翰尼！
I have some new notes that go with the Tito footage for Fred.
我有些新的备注和提托的资料相配 留给弗瑞德的
Fred's gonna be in in an hour.
弗瑞德一小时后到
I already put them on his desk. Can you just make sure that..
我已经放在他的桌子上了 你能帮我确定..
..he doesn't look at the film until he reads the notes?
..他要看了备注之后 才去看胶片？
- Yes. - Thank you.
- 好的 - 谢了
Hey, Joe! Shirley!
嗨，乔！雪莉！
- What's going on in here? - What do you mean?
- 这是怎么了？ - 什么意思？
Two attractive people alone in the copy room!
两位魅力人士单独待在复印室！
Don't tell Paley, he'll fire me.
别告诉佩利，他会炒我
He'll fire both of us, Shirley.
他会炒了我俩，雪莉
- Rules are made to be broken! - You can afford to say that.
- 规矩就是用来打破的！ - 你倒是说得轻巧
Let me see this.
让我看看
- It's simply a loyalty oath. - To CBS? - And to America.
- 不过是个忠诚誓约 - 对CBS？ - 并对美国
You promise to be a loyal American?
你誓言要做一个忠诚的美国人？
I know. All of the reporters have signed this.
我知道，所有的记者都要签
Who are you promising this to? CBS?
向谁起誓？CBS？
Fred signed it. Murrow signed it.
弗瑞德签过了 莫罗签过了
- Murrow signed it? - Yeah.
- 莫罗签过了？ - 是的
Are you now or have you ever been....
你是否现在或者曾经....
I thought it was a joke, but there's a lot of pressure.
起初我以为是个玩笑 可这不是闹着玩得
....on the Attorney General's list of subversive groups?
....在司法部长的颠覆分子名单上？
- I don't know. - Let's think about it.
- 我不知道 - 让我们想想
What is it really saying? Is it a civil liberties issue or censorship?
到底是什么意思？ 这是关于公民自由还是审查制度？
Am I simply stating to CBS that I'm not a Communist?
还是仅仅向CBS表示 我不是共产分子？
- Murrow signed this? - And Fred and Stanton.
- 莫罗签过了？ - 还有弗瑞德和斯坦顿
- Maybe you should talkto Murrow. - Maybe I should sign it.
- 或许你该和莫罗谈谈 - 或许我该签了
If you don't sign this, are you and I a target?
如果不签 你我便成众矢之的？
If I don't sign it, they'll fire me.
如果不签，就会被炒
Sign it.
那签吧
Finally we can tell everyone the truth.
最终我们可以告诉大家实话
If I could express it in what's in my heart now,..
若要我表达此刻我心中所想..
..I'd do it in the terms of the poet who once said,..
..我想借用一位诗人曾经说得..
.."Ah, 'tis but a dainty flower I bring to you."
..“啊，请让我送你一束花朵”
"Yes, 'tis but a violet,.."
“是的，送你一朵绽放…”
"..glistening with dew."
“露水光华的罗兰”
"But still in its heart there lie beauties concealed."
“蓓蕾中蕴含着美丽”
"So in our heart,.."
“正如我们的心中…”
"..our love for you.."
“深藏着…”
"..lies unrevealed."
“对你的热爱”
I used to..
我过去曾..
..pride myself on the idea that I was a bit... tough,..
..为我有些…强硬而感到自豪
..especially overthe past 18-19 months, when we've been..
..尤其是最近的18-19个月 当我们开始..
..kicked around, and bullwhipped, and damned.
..受到粗暴的职责 鞭笞甚至诅咒
I didn't thinkthat..
我认为…
..I could be... touched very deeply.
..我并非一个…容易动摇的人
Okay, that's enough. That's enough, Leo.
够了，够了，里奥
- It's short. - How long is the piece?
- 短了 - 这一段多长？
It's 4 minutes, but we can cut it down.
4分钟，不过我们可以剪掉些
It can't stand alone, but it might be a nice companion piece.
这段孤立了可不好 但会是篇不错的竞选致辞
Let's go through this one more time. Palmer!
让我们再核对一遍，帕默！
Yep, got a call from the office of Senator Morse this morning,..
好，今早接到莫里斯参议员办公室的电话
..interested in setting up a debate possibly with Senator Kerr..
..表示有兴趣和参议员科尔进行一场辩论
..over the comments Bentsen made on last night's show.
..关于本森昨晚节目做的评论
Secretary of Agriculture? Good idea! Can they do it by this week?
农业部部长？好主意！ 他们这周能上节目吗？
No, it would have to be 2 weeks at the earliest,..
不行，最早也要两周后..
..depending on Morse's schedule. But still it's a great idea.
..取决于莫里斯的日程安排 可主意确实不错
Let's follow up on that. "Hoover speaks on Benjamin Franklin."
我们这样定标题好了 “胡佛评价本杰明 富兰克林”
We're having better luck with Mr. Benjamin Franklin..
和胡佛先生相比 我们与本杰明 富兰克林
..than with Mr. Hoover.
..的日子会好过些
It may progress better as a "Person to Person".
这可能对“面对面”有推进作用
"At home with Ben Franklin. His electricity awards."
“家家需要富兰克林 因为他对电的研究”
We've got the footage, we need to contact him.
我们有新闻资料了 需要联系他
See if you can contact him and get the shot. He wants to do the story. Joe!
试试看你能否联系上他并且拍摄 他愿意上这档节目，乔！
Member Delbert Clark?. No longer with us.
还记得埃尔伯特 克拉克？ 已经不和我们一起了
- New YorkTimes? - Yeah. - Our friend at the Times.
- 纽约时报？ - 嗯 - 我们在时报的朋友
This was yesterday morning, they're saying it's....
那是昨天早晨 他们说....
- How old was he? - 53. Sudden illness.
- 他多大年纪？ - 53，突发疾病
- Home of a friend. - No, it's not an obit piece.
- 在朋友家 - 不，那可不是讣告
Natalie send some flowers over there from us.
娜塔莉替我们去送些花
Couple things. Case before the Supreme Court..
还有呢 最高法院正受理..
..involving the constitutionality of a section of the Internal Security Act..
..牵涉到宪法条款的国内安全法
..provides for the deportation of any alien..
..该法案要求有权遣返任何外国人
..if he becomes a Communist after entering this country.
..只要入境后他们加入了共产党
Can you take this?
你们买帐吗？
All right. McCarthy interrupting his wedding trip..
还有，麦卡锡中断了他的新婚旅行..
..to take charge of the investigation of Communist infiltration....
..以主管对共产分子渗透的调查....
- Natalie, send some flowers. - Poor Mrs. McCarthy!
- 娜塔莉，去送些花 - 可怜的麦卡锡夫人！
May I finish? It's national security!
容我说完好吗？ 事关国家安全
- A real ladies' man! - Well, they're in love.
- 好个招女人喜欢的男人！ - 呵呵，他们相爱
We have no show for Tuesday, fellows. So get out there and make some news.
周二还没节目，伙计们 所以都加油找些素材
Rob a bank. Mug an old lady. Do something.
抢银行，劫老妇 想想办法
- You look at the Secretary Stevens footage? - We will.
- 你们看了斯蒂文斯部长的新闻资料了？ - 会看得
Watch it all the way to the end, it's worth it.
从头到尾都看一遍 值得的
Thank you, John.
谢了，约翰
There's not much there.
没什么新闻了
I can't tie it to the Eisenhower in the back of the train piece.
我可不能指望艾森豪威尔 幕后操纵之类的报道
- You ever spend any time in Detroit, Fred? - Not recently.
- 你在底特律待过吗？弗瑞德？ - 最近没
There's a story here in the Detroit News, Dexter, Michigan.
在那有个素材 密歇根的德克斯特，底特律新闻报
A kid named Milo Radulovich.
孩子名叫米洛 瑞杜维奇
- Italian? - Irish. Air Force kicked him out because his dad..
- 意大利裔？ - 爱尔兰裔，空军将他扫地出门
..read some Serbian newspaper. - Was he a Communist? - I don't know.
..因为他父亲读了些塞尔维亚报纸 - 他爸是共产分子？ - 我不知道
- Who brought the charges? - Air Force.
- 谁提起的指控？ - 空军
Charges were in a sealed envelope, nobody saw them.
指控装在一个密封的信封内 没人见过
- Not even at the hearing? - He was declared guilty without a trial..
- 即便是在听证会上？ - 他未经庭审便被判有罪..
..and told if he wanted to keep his job..
..且被告知若想保住饭碗..
..he had to denounce his father and his sister. Thank you, Natalie.
..则必须公开谴责他的父亲和妹妹 谢谢，娜塔莉
- His sister? - He told them to take a hike.
- 他妹妹？ - 他让他们避一避
Let's send Joe and Charlie down there, see if he's any good on camera.
派乔和查理去那 看看他上镜如何
Is he being brought before the Committee?
他接受过委员会的质询了？
No.
没
Then it's not McCarthy.
那和麦卡锡无关了
Isn't it?
是吗？
Milo Radulovich.
米洛 瑞杜维奇
What happens to your children,..
这对你5岁的和..
..your 5-year-old and your 5-month-old in terms of you?
..5个月大的孩子有什么影响？ 对你来说
If I am being judged on my relatives,..
如果要我的亲人来评判我..
..are my children going to be asked to denounce me?
..那么我的孩子们是不是 也被要求公开谴责我？
Are they going to be judged on what their father was labeled?
那他们是不是也要因为 他们父亲的定性而受到评判？
Are they going to have to explain to their friends, etc..
他们是不是要向他们的朋友解释..
..why their father is a security risk?
..为什么他们的父亲是危险分子？
If the thing is let stand as it, the first recommendation,..
如果事情到了这个地步 委员会给出了..
..was sent out by the board, I see a chain reaction that..
..第一建议 那么我看到了事关所有人，任何人..
..has no end to anybody, for anybody.
..无休止的连锁反应
Well, that's new.
嗯，这就是新发现
You can't call this a neutral piece.
你不能称之为中立的报道
The other side's been represented rather well for the last 2 years.
对立的一面在近两年里面 口碑一直很好
The Air Force hasn't gone on the record.
空军从未有过污点
So you want to forego the standards you've stuckto for 1 5 years,..
那么你是想越过 你已经坚守了15年的标准..
..both sides, no commentary.
..这两方，均无解说词
- We all editorialize. - I'm just making sure we identify what....
- 我们都插入编者意见 - 我是想肯定我们确认了....
We're giving them the information up front,..
预先给他们的消息..
..and we're asking them to comment on it.
..然后要求他们对此进行评论
Frank, hold on.
弗兰克，等等
I've searched my conscience.
凭良心讲…
I can't for the life of me find any justification for this.
我实在看不出来那故事 里面有什么正当的理由
I simply cannot accept that there are, on every story,..
我就是无法接受 每个故事里面…
..two equal and logical sides to an argument.
..的争论都可以有对等 合理的两派
- Call it editorializing, if you'd like. - It is editorializing.
- 叫它编者意见，若你想的话 - 这就是编者意见
They'll have equal time to defend themselves.
他们都有均等的机会 为自己辩解
Do you understand the position you're putting us in?
你知不知道你在把我们推进 怎样的境地？
We are all in this together, if the Senate wants to investigate....
我们都是在一条船上 如果参议院要调查....
Do me a favor,..
帮帮忙，弗瑞德..
..avoid any big speeches about how we're all in a big boat together!
..别说什么我们在一条船上 之类的大话！
Please, don't insult me.
拜托，别侮辱我
I have to go back to Mr. Paley and Alcoa, who sponsors your show..
我得去找佩利先生 和Alcoa公司，他们赞助你的节目..
..and also have some military contracts,..
..且与军方有商业合同..
..and I have to tell them that they're going to be in a tough bind..
..而我不得不告诉他们 接下来的处境会很困难..
..because of a beef you had with Joe McCarthy.
..就因为你要对乔 麦卡锡发牢骚了
- We're not going at McCarthy. - You're starting the goddamn fire.
- 我们并非针对麦卡锡 - 你们已经他妈的开火了
Excuse me. Mr. Friendly, there's a Colonel Anderson to see you?
对不起，弗莱德利先生 有位安德森上校要见你
- Colonel? - He's in your office. There are two of them.
- 上校？ - 在你的办公室 有两位
Maybe they liked the transcript, and want to compliment us on it.
没准他们你喜欢你的新闻辞 而且要问候我们
Excuse me.
失陪
Go after Joe Kennedy. We'll pay for it.
去找乔 肯尼迪的麻烦吧 我们来承担后果
I've got a great story about Hoover.
我有关于胡佛的大新闻
You know how many shows you're going to have to do..
你知不知道你需要做 多少档“面对面”..
..to make up for this? - And Judy and her daughter Liza next week.
..以弥补这期节目？ - 还有下周和朱蒂以及她女儿莉莎的节目
No, no. You're interviewing Rin Tin Tin!
不，不 你要去采访Rin Tin Tin（虚构的义犬）！
I'll talk to Mr. Paley.
我去和佩利先生谈
Alcoa won't pay for the ads.
Alcoa（公司）不会为广告费买单
And we probably won't either. But nobody'll stop you.
而公司可能也不会 不过没人会阻止你做节目
How much are the ads?
广告费有多少？
- 3,000. - I'll split it with Fred.
- 3000块 - 我和弗瑞德分摊
He just won't have Christmas presents for his kids this year.
他只不过今年不必为孩子 买圣诞礼物了
- He's a Jew. - Don't tell him that, he loves Christmas.
- 他可是犹太人（暗指吝啬，开玩笑） - 别告诉他，他喜欢圣诞节
- To be clear, you did speak with the lawyers? - Yes, we did.
- 说清楚了，你们确实和律师谈过了？ - 是的，谈过了
And we read the transcript. We've not been allowed to see the footage.
并且我们看过新闻辞 我们未被允许看资料画面
Mack is on a plane from Dexter right now with the last interviews.
节目仍在制作中，查理和麦克正带着 最后的访谈从德克斯特返回
We'll be going right down to the wire.
我们马上就要制作完成了
Your show airs tomorrow. How can we possibly approve and check..
你们的节目明天就播出了 而你给我们的时间实在有限..
..your story in the limited amount of time you have given us?
..我们怎么可能去 检查和批准你的节目？
With all due respect, you have been invited to participate in this piece,..
恕我直言，请你们来是 参与节目..
..not to approve it.
..而不是审核
We are going with the story that says that the U.S. Air Force..
我们的节目讲述的是 美国空军..
..tried Milo Radulovich without any evidence..
..在没有确凿证据的条件下 审查米洛 瑞杜维奇..
..and found him guilty of being a security risk,..
..且认定他作为危险分子而有罪..
..without his Constitutional rights.... - You have not seen the evidence..
..况且他的公民权.... - 你也没有见过证据..
..and are claiming he's not a security risk.
..但你声称他并非 危险分子
Wouldn't you guess that those who have seen the contents of that envelope..
那么是否你该认为 只有那些看过信封内资料
..might have a better idea of what makes someone a danger to his country?
..的人士才对他有更好的判断呢？
- Who? Who? - Or do you think it should just be you that decides?
- 谁？谁？ - 要么你以为只有你才有权来判断？
Who are the people? Are they elected? Are they appointed?
那些人是谁？ 他们是选举出来的？还是委派的？
Do they have an axe to grind? Is it you, sir?
他们是不是别有用心？ 是你吗？先生
Or you, Colonel Jenkins? Do you know the contents of that sealed envelope?
还是你，詹金斯上校？ 你了解那密封信封内的资料吗？
We have been a friend and ally of both Mr. Murrow and CBS News for many years.
弗莱德利先生，多年来我们一直都是 莫罗先生和CBS新闻台的伙伴和盟友
The story you are going to run tomorrow is without merit.
可你们明天要播的节目 没有任何的好处
So before you take any steps that cannot be undone,..
在你要做出 无法挽回的决定之前..
..I strongly urge you to reconsider your stand.
..我强烈建议你 仔细考虑你的立场
These are very dangerous waters you are attempting to navigate.
你正试图走进的领域 好似一片危险的雷场
We have had no hearing at all. We have had no day in court.
而事实就是，根本没有听证会 也没有开过一次庭
In all the 32 years that I have been a practicing attorney in Detroit,..
在我32年的底特律律师 执业生涯里..
..I have never witnessed such a farce and travesty upon justice..
..事态发展到现在 我从未见证过..
..as this thing has developed.
..司法领域发生 如此滑稽荒唐的事情
- Now this whole theory.... - Eddie, just take the first reel.
- 现在，全部的臆测.... - 埃迪，就拿第一卷好了
Tell John I left 5 seconds extra leader.
告诉约翰我在前面 留下了5秒钟空档
5 seconds! I got it! Palmer, where's Joe? Have you seen Joe?
5秒！收到！帕默 乔在哪？你看到乔了？
He's on his way to the control room.
他正去控制室的路上
We're gonna have to do the voice-over live.
我们得做直播的画外音
Natalie, I need a booth with a live mic.
娜塔莉，我要间有麦克风的工作间
Booth is there, it's already set.
工作间在这，都安排好了
We didn't have time to sync the voice-over out.
我们没时间去同步画外音了
That's not what I asked for.
这不是我要求的
It's missing the voice-over on the last piece.
最后一段还差画外音
There's a commercial in the booth. What shall I do?
工作间里有个广告经纪人 我该怎么办？
- 2 minutes to air! - There's not supposed to be a commercial!
- 2分钟后直播！ - 不该有广告经纪的！
Get him out of the booth!
把他赶出去！
2-and-a-half minutes on the end piece.
最后一段时长2分半
Keep it down, please. It's a little loud.
声音小点，拜托 有点吵了
2 minutes to air, fellas.
2分钟后直播，伙计们
- He's gonna add a joke. - Charlie, loan me your lighter.
- 他要加个笑话 - 查理，借个火
Make sure you know that I swap with those two pieces of parents.
确认他知道 我把那两段对调了
- As long as he talks fast because.... - He will talkfast.
- 只要他语速快些，因为.... - 他会快的
We got the film.
胶片来了
Will it be ready?
都准备好了？
You bet.
当然
Funny thing, Freddy!
有趣，弗瑞德！
Every time you light a cigarette for me, I know you're lying.
每次你为我点火 我就知道你在撒谎
It occursto me we might not get away with this one.
我有种预感 这回的麻烦我们躲不过了
Alcoa, the aluminum company of America....
Alcoa，美国铝合金公司....
- 1 0 seconds. - You fellas, ready? Okay.
- 10秒钟 - 你们准备好了？好
Ready on camera 1.
1号摄像机准备
5, 4, 3, 2.
5, 4, 3, 2
Pan, camera 1.
1号机
Good evening.
晚上好
A few weeks ago there occurred a few obscure notices in the newspapers..
数周前，报纸上发表了 一些含糊的报道…
..about Milo Radulovich,..
..关于米洛 瑞杜维奇..
..a lieutenant in the Air Force Reserves.
..一位现役美国空军中尉
And, also, something aboutAir Force regulation 35-62,..
以及，关于空军规章35-62条款..
..which states that a man may be regarded as a security risk..
..规定任何与共产分子 有紧密或持续接触
..if he has close and continuing association with Communists..
..或者被认做是同情共产主义者的
..or people believed to have Communist sympathies.
..都将被视作为危险分子
Lieutenant Radulovich was asked to resign in August. He declined.
瑞杜维奇中尉被要求在8月辞职 他拒绝了
A board was called and heard his case.
一个委员会组建并开始调查
At the end it was recommended that he be severed from the Air Force,..
事情的结果是 虽然对于中尉的忠诚…
..although it was also stated that there was no question whatever..
..没有任何异议 可委员会仍旧建议将中尉…
..as to the Lieutenant's loyalty.
..驱逐出空军部队
We propose to examine, in so far as we can,..
力所能及地 我们开始审视…
..the case of Lieutenant Radulovich.
..瑞杜维奇中尉的案件
Our reporter, Joe Wershba, cameraman, Charlie Mack.
请看记者乔 沃什 摄影师查理 麦克的报道
This is the town of Dexter, Michigan. Population 1 500.
这里是密歇根州的德克斯特镇 人口1500
This statue is at the end of Ann Arbor Street erected by....
这座矗立在安阿伯街尽头 的雕塑是由....
What did the General tell you yesterday?
将军昨天和你说什么了？
- A Colonel. There were two of them. - That makes a General.
- 是上校，两个上校 - 那就算一个将军
They weren't too pleased.
他们不是很高兴
You're gonna get audited this year.
你今年要接受考核了
Not me, you. I told them I didn't want to do the story.
不是我，是你 我告诉他们我不想做这档节目的
- You always were yellow. - Better than red.
- 你总是黄色的（胆怯的） - 总好过赤色的
In 10 seconds.
还有10秒
This is the sister, Margaret Radulovich Fishman.
这位是妹妹 玛格丽特 瑞杜维奇 菲舍曼
She neither defends nor explains her political activities.
她既不辩解、也不说明 她的政治活动
I feel that my activities, be what they may,..
不管他们怎么想 我觉得我的活动
..or my political beliefs are my own private affair.
..或者我的政治信仰 都是我自己的事情
Are my children going to be asked to denounce me?
我的孩子们是不是 也被要求公开谴责我？
Are they going to be judged on what their father was labeled?
那他们是不是也要因为 他们父亲的定性而受到评判？
Are they going to have to explain to their friends, etc..
他们是不是要向他们的朋友解释..
..why their father is a security risk?
..为什么他们的父亲 是危险分子？
I see, absolutely, that this is a chain reaction.
我觉得，这肯定会是连锁反应
If the thing is let stand as it, the first recommendation,..
如果事情到了这个地步 委员会给出了..
..was sent out by the board I see a chain reaction..
..第一建议 那么我看到了事关所有人，任何人..
..that has no end to anybody, for anybody.
..无休止的连锁反应
Perhaps you will permit me to read a few sentences..
请允许我 朗读下面的稿子..
..because I would like to say rather precisely what I mean.
..因为我想非常准确地 表达出我要说的话
We have told the Air Force that we will provide facilities..
我们已经告知美国空军 我们愿意..
..for any comments, criticisms, or corrections it may wish to make..
..为他们针对米洛 瑞杜维奇案件的..
..as to the case of Milo Radulovich.
..任何评论、反驳或者勘误提供平台
We are unable to judge the charges against his father or sister..
我们没有资格去评判 针对他父亲、他妹妹的指控..
..because neither we, nor you, nor they, nor the lawyers,..
..因为我们、你们、他们、律师们..
..northe Lieutenant, knowwhatwas contained in that manila envelope.
..还有中尉本人，都不知道 那信封里面的确切内容
Was it hearsay, rumor, gossip, slander,..
那么，所有的流言、蜚语 道听、途说..
..or hard ascertainable facts that could be backed by credible witnesses?
..或者难以探知的真相会因为 可靠的证人而变得真实有力吗？
We do not know.
我们不得而知
We believe the son shall not bear the iniquity of the father.
但我们相信孩子不应 为父亲而背负偏见
Even though that iniquity be proved and in this case it was not.
即使对父亲的指控成立 且在本案中并未如此
But we believe too that this case illustrates the urgent need..
我们同时也坚信 本案也映射出一种迫切的需要..
..for the Armed Forces to communicate more fully than they have so far done..
..那就是相对于目前的作为
..the procedures and regulations to be followed..
…美国三军应当更加充分沟通
..in attempting to protect the national security..
..在努力保护国家安全的同时
..and the rights of the individual at the same time.
..保护公民个人的权利
Whatever happens in this area of the relationship..
无论这起国家与个人的事件
..between the individual and the state,..
..进展到什么地步
..we will do it ourselves,..
..都是我们自己的事务
..it cannot be blamed on Malenkov or Mao Tse-Tung or even our allies.
..不能归咎于马林科夫（苏俄政治家） 或毛泽东甚至我们的盟友
And, it seems to us, Fred Friendly and myself,..
并且，对于编者自己 弗瑞德 弗莱德利和我本人..
..that this is a subject that should be argued about endlessly.
..这也会是一个 持续议论下去的话题
Good night, and good luck.
祝您晚安，好运
And we're out.
直播结束
May I tell you something about yourself..
让我来跟您这个“面对面”的观众…
..as a member of the "Person to Person" audience?
..说说关于您的事情吧
Based on audience research studies,..
据观众研究调查显示
..you are well above average in education and intelligence.
..您的教育与智商均优于平均水平
Your interests are wide, from world affairs and science..
您兴趣广泛 从世界时事到科学探索..
..to sports and show business.
..再到体育和娱乐业
And you have one characteristic that's rather encouraging to me..
而正是由于您 不会盲从于广告的特性
..and that's the fact that you are not easily persuaded by advertising.
使得我更有兴趣与您交流
The makers of Kent considered all these characteristics..
健牌香烟充分了解您的特性
..when they chose Mr. Murrow's program..
..因此选择莫罗先生的节目
..to tell you about Kent.
..跟您聊聊健牌
Of all leading filter cigarettes, Kent filters best.
精良过滤嘴香烟 唯有健牌
If you try Kent with that in mind, I think you'll agree..
如果您选择了健牌 我想您就会明白..
..with many other thinking people who have changed to Kent.
其他许多格调人士 为什么也选择健牌了
They find that it makes good sense to smoke Kent and good smoking, too.
他们发现健牌在手 拥有的，不仅仅是香烟
- Did you get the changes? - Edward Murrow, "Person to Person",..
- 你知道改动了吗？ - 爱德华 莫罗，“面对面”..
..on the CBS Television Network. - No, no. You there? Okay. We got it.
..CBS新闻网 - 不，不，你在吗？好，我们知道了
Now backto Ed Murrow.
画面切回到艾德 莫罗
Not since the silent movies and the idols they produced..
早在默片和偶像出现之前
..has Hollywood witnessed the sort of pilgrimage that is now going on.
..好莱坞就已经见证了 类似朝圣般的事情了
Each day, oblivious to time, weather, and the state of the world,..
每天，不论任何时间 天气以及世界局势
..sightseers head in the direction of California's San Fernando Valley.
..观光客涌向加州圣费尔南多谷
For there, at the end of the tourist line, is Sherman Oaks..
在那里，观光线尽头的谢尔曼 奥克斯
..and the home Liberace has built for himself and his mother.
..和影星黎伯拉奇为自己和母亲盖的房子
This is the front and nobody knows how many people have seen that view.
这是正门，不知道多少人见过那风景
This is the back of the house and that's Liberace's bedroom.
这是房子背面 那是黎伯拉奇的卧室
- Good evening, Lee. - Good evening, Ed.
- 晚上好，黎 - 晚上好，艾德
- What are you doing? - I'm dictating my weekly syndicated newspaper column..
- 忙什么呢？ - 我正用录音机口述我的每周专栏..
..and on my trusty tape recorder here, I'm also dictating a book.
..并且还在准备一本书
- It's an inspirational book. - Lee, what about you?
- 有灵感的书 - 黎，你怎么样？
Have you given much thought to getting married and settling down?
有没有想过要结婚并安定下来？
Actually, I've given a lot of thought to it,..
实际上，我确实仔细想过..
..but I don't believe in getting married just for the sake of getting married.
..但我认为不必为了结婚 而去结婚
I want to some day find the perfect mate..
我期望有朝一日能找到 如意的伴侣..
..and settle down to what I hope will be a marriage that will be blessed..
..安定下来结婚 受到衷心的祝福..
..by faith and will be a lasting union.
..并相爱地久天长
I was reading about lovely young Princess Margaret..
事实上，我刚刚读到关于 年轻可爱的玛格丽特公主的文章
..and she's looking for her dream man, too,..
..她也在寻找她的白马王子
..and I hope she finds him some day.
..我希望她能美梦成真
Uh-huh. Lee, thanks very much for letting us come and visit you.
哦，黎，非常感谢 你的招待
It's been very pleasant.
我们玩的很开心
And will you say good night to your family for us?
代我向你的家人问好
- I certainly will. - Thanks a lot.
- 没问题 - 非常感谢
- Good night, Ed. - Good night, Lee.
- 晚安，艾德 - 晚安，黎
Next week, we'll take you to Beverly Hills, California,..
下周，我们将带您去加州贝弗利山..
..to the house of Mickey Rooney and his new bride.
..到米基 鲁尼和他的新娘那里做客
Until then, good night, and good luck.
那么，祝您晚安，好运
Good show, Mr. Murrow!
好节目，莫罗先生
Excuse me, Mr. Murrow.
抱歉，莫罗先生
Could you take a look at this and sign it for me, please?
看一下再签名好吗？
Thank you. Dr. Stanton would like to have a drink with you.
谢谢，斯坦顿博士 想和您喝一杯
- When? - Now. He's at the Pentagon Bar.
- 什么时候？ - 现在，他在五角形酒吧
I can't. What the hell is he doing there?
不行，他在那干吗？
- I believe he's waiting for you. - Just call him! - Fine.
- 我想是在等您 - 就打电话给他吧！- 好
- Oppenheimer next week. - It's a good show, Ed.
- 下周是奥本海默（原子弹之父） - 节目不错，艾德
- Hey, Don! - Ed!
- 嗨，唐！ - 艾德！
You're getting good at this!
你真是越干越强哦
They're gonna think you like it!
他们会以为你喜欢呢
Pays the bills. How are you, Don?
养家糊口而已，你好吗？唐
Ah, it's..
啊，还是..
..day to day.
..老样子
If she saw how good you look right now, she'd be back.
若她知道你现在精神焕发 她会回到你身边的
You tell her that if you see her, will you?
那你看见她了 就告诉她，好吗？
- I read the O'Brian piece. - Yeah, it's tough.
- 我看了奥布莱恩（长期攻击 唐 霍伦贝克的右翼写手）的文章 - 是呀，伤脑筋
I'm a pinko. I slant the news.
我是左派 我歪曲新闻报道
I'm just waiting for him to say my wife left me too.
我就等着他说 我妻子弃我而去了
- Nobody worth their salt reads him. - You read him.
- 他的文章不值一读 - 你读了
Well, see, I rest my case.
唔，瞧，那我不用多说了
- Does Paley read him? - Bill Paley's not gonna do anything.
- 佩利读了吗？ - 比尔 佩利不会怎么样的
Thanks, Ed.
谢谢，艾德
I just came by to tell you how great the Lieutenant piece was.
我过来告诉你 中尉那篇节目做的真棒
- Thanks. - How's the fallout? - Mostly good, surprisingly.
- 谢谢  - 反响如何？ - 反响很好，出乎意料
Is this the start? Are you taking sides?
这只是开始？ 你站在哪派？
It's just a little poke with a stick, see what happens.
投石问路，静观其变
You let me know if I can help.
有事您说话
But you're a pinko.
可你是左派，唐
I'll see you.
回头见
Hey, Joe! What's all this Radulovich junkyou're putting out?
嗨，乔！你搞那些瑞杜维奇的 垃圾是要干吗？
I can't talkto you now. I have to get this film back to NewYork.
现在没空和你说 我得把胶片送回纽约
What would you say if I told you..
如果我告诉你莫罗在1935年时
..that Murrow was on the Soviet payroll in 1935?
..为苏联人工作 你会怎么说？
- Uh! Charlie, you wanna.... - Sure. I'll set up outside.
- 嗯？查理，你要.... - 好，我设在外面
McCarthy going to the Eisenhower dinner?
麦卡锡赴艾森豪威尔的宴？
- I have no idea. I don't keep the Senator's calendar for him! - Really?
- 我不知道，我可不为参议员管理日程 - 是吗？
Have you ever seen any spy films? You don't hand me a classified folder!
看过间谍片吗？ 你不该这么把机密卷宗递给我！
You're supposed to slip it into my briefcase!
你该偷偷塞进我的公事包里！
I didn't know who to give this information to, Paley or Murrow.
这资料我不知道是该给谁 佩利还是莫罗
As you can imagine, Fred and I aren't very friendly. No pun intended.
你能想到，弗瑞德和我合不来 没别的意思
No pun elocuted.
没别的意思才怪！
- What do you got, Donald? - In short?
- 你掌握了什么？唐纳德 - 简单地说？
Murrow's been a Communist sympathizer since the 1930's.
早在1930年开始 莫罗就同情共产分子
Member of the International Workers, sponsored educational trips to Moscow,..
他也是国际工盟的成员 资助前往莫斯科的留学..
..and on the Soviet payroll in 1 935. It's all there.
..并在1935年为苏联工作 上面都有
You wanna know why that's not possible?
你要知道那为什么不可能吗？
Why you'll lose this one?
为什么你们会失败？
Because everyone in this country..
因为这个国家所有人..
..knows that Ed Murrow is a loyal American, he's a patriot.
..都知道艾德 莫罗是个忠诚的美国人 他是爱国者
Did you know the word "gullible" isn't in the dictionary?
你知不知道字典里没有“易受骗的” 这个词？
- Can I give this to him? - I'd love it! I have copies!
- 我可以把这个给他吗？ - 随便你！反正我有复本！
I think you guys go too far.
我想你们是玩过火了
Well, if it walks like a duck, talks like a duck.
如果走路像鸭子 那说话也像鸭子
Yes, Mr. Paley.
好的，佩利先生
Right away. Yes, sir.
马上 是，先生
No, he hasn't called.
不，他还没打电话
Yes, sir, the second he calls. If you're in a meeting, shall I...?
是，先生，如果他再打来 若你在开会，我...？
Yes, sir. Of course, sir.
是的，先生 当然
Mr. Murrow!
莫罗先生
Mr. Paley will see you now.
佩利先生可以见你了
- Mr. Paley, Mr. Murrow is here. - Thanks, Miss Mary.
- 佩利先生，莫罗到了 - 谢谢，玛丽小姐
- Hello, Ed. - Bill... - Sit over here, will you?
- 你好，艾德  - 比尔... - 那边坐，好吗？
How's Janet?
珍妮特好吗？
- Your son? - All well, thanks. How's Babe?
- 你孩子呢？ - 都好，谢谢，贝碧好吗？
She's fine. Her fundraiser got rained on, so....
她很好，只是她的基金捐助 少了很多，所以....
- Oh! That's why I never plan on anything. - Really?
- 哦！这就是我为何从不做计划的原因 - 是吗？
You'd never know.
世事难料
Reading fiction?
读小说（编造）呢？
I hope so. You tell me.
但愿如此，你说呢
Now we know how they're gonna come at us.
现在我们知道 他们如何攻击我们了
That's just the first shot. Somebody's going to go down.
这仅仅是开始而已 总有人会遭殃
Have you checked your facts? Are you on safe ground?
你确信你的背景了？ 你就高枕无忧了？
- Bill, it's time. Show our cards. - My cards.
- 比尔，是时候了，亮出我们的牌 - 是我的牌
You lose, what happens? 5 guys find themselves out of work.
你输了，然后呢？ 5个同事丢了饭碗
I'm responsible for a lot more than 5 goddamn reporters. Let it go.
而除了5个该死的记者，我还要为 其他许多事情负责，你罢手吧
McCarthy will self-destruct, Cohn, all of them.
麦卡锡自己会垮台的 还有科恩（副手），全部
You said Corporate would not interfere with Editorial..
你说过公司不会干涉编者意见的..
..and that the News was to be left....
..还有新闻都应该....
We don't make the news, we report the news.
我们并不制造新闻 我们报道新闻
99% of the time he's wrong about those he's marked as Communists.
99%的情况下，他所指认的共产分子 都是被冤枉的
If he goes too far, the Senate will investigate him..
如果他惹过火了 参议院会调查他..
..and we will report on that.
..而我们也可以去报道
But he's wrong 1 00% of the time when he oversteps people's civil liberties.
可当他践踏公民自由的时候 就是100%的错误！
And you're trying him in the press?
那么你就在媒体上审问他？
Does he get the right to face his accuser?
他有权面对原告了？
You've decided on this and you're presenting it as fact.
你已经做出结论 并且当作事实播出了
- What I am doing.... - I write your check.
- 我所做的… - 是我给你开薪水
I put you in your country house, and I put your son through school!
是我让你可以住乡间别墅 而且是我让你的孩子有书可读！
You should have told me about this before it went so far down the road!
在事情弄到这步田地之前 你本该先通知我
Everyone of your boys needs to be clean. Do you understand? No ties.
你所有的同僚必须根底清白 你懂吗？不能有牵连
If Aaron's mother went to a group fundraiser in 1 932, he's out.
如果亚伦的母亲参加了1932年的筹款会 他就完了
Hewitt, too. Anyone in that room. You make no mistake,..
休伊特也是如此，节目组所有的人 你稍有闪失..
..I will cut them loose. Corporate won't interfere with Editorial.
..我就得炒他们鱿鱼 公司不干涉编者意见
But Editorial will not jeopardize the hundreds of employees..
但是编者意见也不可以 危害到CBS的..
..of the CBS. Do I make myself clear?
..数百名员工 你听明白了吗？
Yes?
哪位？
Fellas, our next show is gonna be about Senator McCarthy.
大伙，我们下一期节目 就是关于参议员麦卡锡的
And we're gonna go right at him.
并且我们将和他针锋相对
I don't need to tell you how careful we have to be.
不用我说，你们也该清楚 我们得有多么小心
If we are to do this, Ed and I need you to be straight with us.
如果这么做，艾德和我 需要你们坦白
We need to know, for the good of the piece,..
为了节目 我们需要知道..
..if any of you have any connection, if you subscribed to a newsletter,..
..你们任何人与（左派）有牵连 订阅过（左派）报纸..
..if you attended a party, anything,..
..参加过（左派）集会 任何的..
..anything that could compromise this, anything at all,..
..任何可能危及节目 所有的事情..
..because now would be the time to tell us.
..现在讲出来还不晚
Ed, I think I should excuse myself.
艾德，我有话得说
Palmer, you kidding?
帕默，开什么玩笑？
My ex was a.... I wouldn't say she was a Communist,..
我前妻曾是.... 我认为她不算是共产分子..
..but she attended meetings. It was before we were married.
..可她参加过集会 在我们结婚之前
I didn't even really know about it until after the divorce.
这我也是直到离婚后才知道得
But it was different then. We were all on the same side.
可后来就不同了 我们站在同一边
I'm not telling you anything you don't know. The thing is..
我不说，你们也不会知道 可问题是..
..somebody'll find out.
..有人会挖出来
They'll hurt us with it.
籍以对付我们
I should have told you sooner, Ed, I'm sorry.
我本该早点告诉你，艾德 我很抱歉
Fred.
弗瑞德
If none of us had ever read a "dangerous" book,..
如果我们都没看过 所谓的“危险”书籍
..or had a friend who was "different",..
..结交持“异见”的朋友
..or never joined an organization that advocated "change",..
..或者从不参加任何 提倡“革新”的组织
..we'd all be the kind of people Joe McCarthy wants.
..那我们就成了乔 麦卡锡 所期望的那类人了
We're gonna go with the story, because the terror is in this room.
这篇报道我们要播 因为恐怖已经笼罩在这个房间里了
John! Jesse! Go through the HUAC hearings.
约翰！杰西！ 仔细检查HUAC（众议院反美调查委员会）的听证会
Eddie! Palmer! Look at who did the interviews and any speeches.
埃迪！帕默！查一查 谁做的访问和演说
Okay, fellas, here we go.
好了，大伙，开工吧
His own words, that's what we need.
他自己的话 才是我们需要的
....said that he wouldn't remove a General from theArmy..
....说道他不会撤掉 一个支持共产主义者少校..
..who supported a Communist Major. I said, "Then, General,.."
..的将军，我说 “那么，将军…
"..you should be removed from any command."
..你应该也被解职”
"Any man who says, 'I will protect and honor a General'.."
“任何声称 我会保护且尊敬 一个支持共产分子…
"..'who protects Communists', is not fit to wear that uniform, General."
..的将军，都不配他那身军服”
Ethically, we're fine.
道理上，并无大碍
But legally, if we air this, are we leaking closed hearing testimony?
可法律上，如果我们播出 算不算泄露非公开听证会的发言？
- But he chose to read it. - We're not misquoting him.
- 可是他自己要读的 - 我们没有断章取义
- There are other reporters. - If it's a legal issue, it's his.
- 也有其他的记者 - 若是法律问题，那也是他自己的
I'll check with Campbell in Legal.
关于法律事宜 我会和坎贝尔确认一下
And wait till you hear the bleeding hearts..
最后等到你的心 那软弱的心
..scream and cry about our methods..
..为我们从那些知道 或应该知道
..from those who know or should know..
..的人那里挖掘真相
..who covered up a Fifth Amendment Communist Major.
的手段而呼喊和流泪
But they say, "Oh,.."
可他们说，“哦…
"..it's all right to uncover them, but don't get rough doing it, McCarthy."
..揭露他们可没什么 可不要太粗暴，麦卡锡”
Did a Civil Liberties Union provide you with an attorney at that time?
在那时民权联盟为你指派 了律师吗？
I had many offers of attorneys..
我有很多律师可以选择..
..and from the American Civil Liberties Union, too. - The questions is:
..并且也有来自民权联盟的 - 我的问题是：
..did the Civil Liberties Union supply you with an attorney?
..民权联盟为你指派 了律师吗？
- They did supply an attorney. - The answer is yes?
- 他们是指派了一名律师 - 那回答就是 是？
The answer is yes.
是的
You know the Civil Liberties Union has been listed..
你知道民权联盟被列作是..
..as a front for and doing the work of the Communist Party?
..共产党组织并为共产党工作？
Mr. Chairman, this was 1932!
主席先生，那可是1932年！
I know this was in 1932.
我知道那是1932年
Do you know that they since have been listed..
你知道自从那以后 他们被列作是..
..as a front for and doing the work of the Communist Party?
..共产党组织并为共产党工作？
I do not know that they have been listed so, sir.
我不知道他们被列作那样的组织，先生
- You don't know? - I have heard that mentioned....
- 你不知道？ - 我曾听过有人说起....
All right, Leo. Turn it off.
好了，里奥，关掉
- I need those three cans of Stevens! - Has anybody read this book yet?
- 我需要那三盒关于斯蒂文斯的胶片！ - 你们有人读过这本书吗？
It would be nice if this guy isn't a Commie.
若这家伙不是赤共 就好了
- Did Millie give it to you? - I wanna read the book.
- 米莉给你了吗？ - 我要读那本书
- Nobody else, Joe. - I hear you, boss.
- 没别人了，乔 - 我听到了，老板
I'll put it on a kinescope, push through the end.
我会把它放在录像里 贯穿到结束
Palmer, cut it at 2:30.
帕默，剪到2分半
I prefer it one on each end, let it run through.
我希望每个结尾各一个 贯穿一下
It'd be more powerful. Cut Kennedy?
会更有力，剪掉肯尼迪？
Joe, file it for me. I'll see the Mundt piece later.
乔，帮我备好材料 我回头去看穆特的资料
Are we gonna make it, Fred?
我们能完成吗？弗瑞德
We lost the telecine, but we'll make it.
我们没了电视电影 不过会完成的
Did you finish your closing piece?
你准备好结束辞了？
It's Shakespeare.
引用莎翁
Write your closing.
写你的结束辞
My argument was if you just show the images of McCarthy..
我的意见是 是否播出麦卡锡的画面..
..it doesn't make any difference.
..不会有什么差别
If you agree with him, you're gonna hate the piece.
如果你赞同麦卡锡 你会恨这节目
If you don't, you'll love it.
如果你反对 那你会喜欢这节目
Maybe they should wait till they get more footage.
或许他们该等到 有更多的资料片段
I don't think we can take that chance.
我认为没可能有更多了
We've got to hit McCarthy before he comes after Ed.
在麦卡锡对付艾德之前 我们得痛击麦卡锡
The blue one. They haven't gone after the Alsops or Herb Block.
戴蓝的吧，他们还没找 奥尔索普或赫布 布洛克的麻烦
Honey, the Alsops and Herb Block..
亲爱的，奥尔索普或赫布 布洛克..
..didn't work for the Institute of International Education in 1 934.
..在1934年可没为 国际教育学院工作
Then I guess it's time.
那我猜是时候了
You worried?
你担心了？
I didn't think I was.
我想我没
I don't know why. I was in the office on Friday.
不知道为什么 周五在办公室的时候
And I answered the phone, it was Howard calling from London.
我接霍华德从伦敦打来的电话
And he asked what was going on with McCarthy.
他问我麦卡锡的事情进展
And before I answered him, I turned and looked over my shoulder..
在回答之前，我先转身四下张望..
..to see who was listening. - And who was listening?
..看是否隔墙有耳 - 有谁在听？
Chairman Mao...
毛主席..
I'll see you at the office.
办公室见
- Hey, your ring! - Uh!
- 嘿，你的婚戒！ - 嗯！
Name me another wife..
你说哪位太太..
..who reminds her husband to take off his wedding ring..
..在丈夫出门上班前..
..before he goes to the office. - Ava Gardner.
..要提醒他摘掉戒指的 - 艾娃 嘉德纳（女星）
Excuse me, Mr. Friendly. Mr. Murrow, Mr. Paley's on the line for you.
对不起，弗莱德利先生 莫罗先生，佩利先生来电
- Maybe he wants to reimburse us for those ads. - You'd like that!
- 没准他是想替我们把广告费给垫了 - 你想的美！
- I would like that! - This is Ed.
- 我是那么想的 - 我是艾德
There's a Knickerbocker game tonight. I've got front row seats.
今晚有棒球赛 我有前排座位
Are you interested?
你有兴趣？
I'm busy bringing down the network tonight, Bill.
我正忙着搞垮公司呢，比尔
Is that tonight?
是今晚吗？
We're covered, Bill.
我们瞒着你的，比尔
All right.
那好
- I'm with you today, Ed, and I'm with you tomorrow. - Thanks, Bill.
- 今天我支持你，艾德，以后也会 - 谢谢，比尔
Do you know the timing on the first piece?
知道第一段新闻辞的时长吗？
Can we hold all the calls, please?
把电话机都掐了，好吗？
Hold the calls till after the show. Thank you.
把电话都掐了，直到节目结束 谢谢
- You fellas, awake down there? - Okay.
- 你们大伙，都清醒吗？ - 好了
- Just... what are we? 20? - 30 seconds, Ed.
- 还有，还有多久？20？ - 30秒准备，艾德
1 0 seconds.
10秒
5, 4, 3, 2.
5，4，3，2
And pan, camera one.
开拍，一号机
Because a report on Senator McCarthy is by definition controversial,..
由于对参议员麦卡锡的 节目富有争议..
..we want to say exactly what we mean to say..
..我们想确切的表达我们的意思..
..and request your permission to read from a script..
..请允许我朗读下面的手稿
..whatever remarks Murrow and Friendly may make.
..以叙述莫罗和弗莱德利 想要表达的内容
If the Senator feels that we have done violence to his words or pictures..
如果参议员认为我们的节目 歪曲了他的讲话、形象..
..and desires to answer himself,..
并且他要为自己申辩..
..an opportunity will be afforded him on this program.
我们欢迎他上我们的节目
Our working thesis tonight is this quotation:
我们今晚的主题来自于 这段引语：
.."If this fight against Communism.."
..“如果这场针对共产分子的斗争…”
"..has made a fight between America's two great political parties,.."
..演变成美国最大的 两个政党之间的斗争
"..theAmerican people know that one of these parties will be destroyed.."
美国民众清楚其中 有一个政党将被摧毁
"..and the Republic cannot endure very long as a one-party system."
并且在一党制的情形下 共和党（麦卡锡所属）也不会坚持很久
We applaud that statement..
我们为这段声明喝彩
..and we think Senator McCarthy ought to.
..并且我们认为 参议员麦卡锡也应如此
He said it 17 months ago in Milwaukee.
17个月前在米尔沃基他这样说道
TheAmerican people realize that this cannot be made a fight..
美国大众明白这不会演变成..
..between America's two great political parties.
..美国最伟大的两个政党之间的斗争
If this fight against Communism..
如果这场针对共产分子的斗争
..is made a fight againstAmerica's two great political parties,..
..演变成美国最伟大的 两个政党之间的斗争
..theAmerican people know that one of those parties will be destroyed..
..美国人民清楚 其中之一将被摧毁
..and the Republic can't endure very long as a one-party system.
..并且共和党在一党制情形下 也不会坚持太久
On one thing the Senator has been consistent.
而参议员不遗余力地…
Often operating as a one-man committee, he has traveled far,..
作为一个单人的委员会 四处寻访
..interviewed many, terrorized some,..
..访谈很多人 恐吓部分人..
..accused civilian and military leaders..
..控告过去任职的..
..of the past administration of a great conspiracy..
..行政官员和军队领导阴谋要..
..to turn over the country to Communism.
..将国家颠覆成共产主义
I was extremely shocked when I heard that Secretary Stevens..
当我听说斯蒂文斯部长
..told 2Army officers that they had to take part in the cover up..
..通知两位军官参与到掩盖
..of those who promoted and coddled Communists.
..那些提升和纵容共产分子的事情 我非常震惊
As I read his statement, I..
当我读他的声明时
..thought of that quotation, "On what meat.."
..我想到了这样的话语 “到底是何种肉…
"..doth this our Caesar feed?".
…喂给了我们的恺撒？”（莎士比亚 《恺撒传》）
The questions is:
问题是：
..did the Civil Liberties Union supply you with an attorney?
..民权联盟有没有 为你找律师？
- They did supply an attorney. - The answer is yes?
- 他们确实为我找律师 - 你回答是？
The answer is yes.
是的
Do you think this book did considerable harm?
你认为这本书 造成了客观的损害吗？
Its publication,..
还有它的出版..
..by an expression of the views contained in it?
..以及书中所表达的观点？
The sale of that book was so abysmally small,..
那本书的销量非常有限
..it was so unsuccessful, that the question of its influence....
..很不成功 至于那本书的影响....
You can go back to the publisher,..
你可以去问出版商..
..you'll see it was one of the most unsuccessful books he ever put out.
..你会明白那是他所出版 的最差劲的书
He's still sorry about it, just as I am.
他还是为之感到遗憾 同样我也是
Well, I thinkthat's a compliment toAmerican intelligence.
那么，我看倒是对美国大众 民智的恭维
I'll say that.
我这么说
The Reed Harris hearing demonstrates one of the Senator's techniques.
里德 哈里斯听证会显示出 参议员（麦卡锡）的一个手段
Twice he said,..
两次他说道..
.."The American Civil Liberties Union was listed as a subversive front."
..“美国民权联盟被列作是 颠覆分子组织”
The Attorney General's list does not and never has listed..
然而司法部并未，且从未..
..theACLU as subversive, nor does the FBI,..
..将民盟列作是颠覆组织 FBI也没有..
..or any other federal government agency.
..以及任何其他政府机构都未如此
And the American Civil Liberties Union holds in its files..
并且美国民权联盟手中握有 他们的文件..
..letters of commendation from President Truman,..
..也就是杜鲁门总统..
..President Eisenhower, and General MacArthur.
..艾森豪威尔总统，麦克阿瑟将军 的褒奖令
Earlier, the Senator asked, "Upon what meat does this our Caesar feed?".
早前，参议员问道，“到底是 何种肉喂给了我们的恺撒”？
Had he looked three lines earlier in Shakespeare's "Caesar"..
如果他在莎士比亚的《恺撒传》里 往上看三行
..he would have found this line, which is not altogether inappropriate.
..他便会找到这句台词 总之不会不相称
"The fault, dear Brutus, is not in our stars, but in ourselves."
“亲爱的布鲁图斯（行刺恺撒者），这过错 并非在于星辰，而是在于我们自己”
No one familiar with the history of this country..
任何熟悉我们这个国家历史的人..
..can deny that Congressional committees are useful.
..都不能否认国会委员会的重要性
It is necessary to investigate before legislating,..
在立法之前进行调查 是必要的..
..but the line between investigating and persecuting is a very fine one..
..可调查与迫害之间 的界线也是分明的..
..and the junior Senator from Wisconsin has stepped over it repeatedly.
..而这位来自威斯康星的下级参议员（麦卡锡） 却再三地越过这条界线
We must not confuse dissent with disloyalty.
我们不可以将反对的声音 视作背叛
We must remember always that accusation is not proof..
我们必须时刻牢记 指控并不等于证据..
..and that conviction depends upon evidence and due process of law.
..并且定罪必须基于 铁证和适当的法律程序
We will not walk in fear, one of another.
我们不会从一类恐怖 步入另一类
We will not be driven by fear into an age of unreason..
如果仔细探究我们的历史和原则
..if we dig deep in our history and doctrine,..
..并且铭记我们并非天生畏惧
..and remember that we are not descended from fearful men,..
畏惧写作、团结、说话
..not from men who feared to write, to associate, to speak,..
..和捍卫暂时不受肯定的事业
..and to defend the causes that were for the moment unpopular.
..我们便不会被恐惧 所驱使进一个无理性的时代
This is no time for men who oppose Senator McCarthy's methods..
对于任何反对参议员麦卡锡 或者赞同他的人而言
..to keep silent, or for those who approve.
..现在都不该保持沉默
We can deny our heritage and our history,..
我们或许可以否定 我们的传统和历史
..but we cannot escape responsibility for the results.
..可终究逃脱不了 这一切后果带来的责任
We proclaim ourselves, indeed as we are,..
确实如我们所做的那样 无论在哪里..
..the defenders of freedom wherever it continues to exist in the world,..
..我们都将自己看作是自由的捍卫者
..but we cannot defend freedom abroad by deserting it at home.
..可我们不能在国外捍卫自由 却在自己的家园里弃之于不顾
The actions of the junior Senator from Wisconsin..
这位来自威斯康星 下级参议员的所作所为
..have caused alarm and dismay amongst our allies abroad..
..已经引起我们盟友的 警觉和不安
..and given considerable comfort to our enemies.
..且让我们的敌人感到快意
And whose fault is that? Not really his.
这是谁的错？ 不全是他的错
He didn't create this situation of fear,..
他并没有制造这 恐怖的局势
..he merely exploited it, and rather successfully.
..他只不过是借机利用 且相当成功而已
Cassius was right.
卡西乌斯（刺杀恺撒者）是对的
"The fault, dear Brutus, is not in our stars, but in ourselves."
“亲爱的布鲁图斯，这过错 并非在于星辰，而是在于我们自己”
Good night, and good luck.
祝您晚安，好运
And we're out.
直播结束
Nothing?
风平浪静？
Maybe nobody watched.
可能都没人看
- We got nothing. - I don't know. - Nothing.
- 没什么 - 我不知道  - 没什么
Should I turn the phones back on, Mr. Williams?
要不要我把电话给接上？威廉姆斯先生
Yes. Now would be a good time for that.
好，现在接吧
Turn the phones on! Turn the pho --
把电话接上！
Mr. Friendly wants the phones on.
弗莱德利先生要求把电话接上
It's the Junior Senator calling collect.
这里是下级参议员付费电话
Don't kid yourself. It's Reed Harris thanking us for mentioning him.
别耍嘴皮子了，是里德 哈里斯 感谢我们在节目中提到他了
I don't know whether all of you have seen what I just saw,..
我不知道你们是不是都看了 我刚才看到的节目
..but I want to associate myself and this program..
..可我想就刚才艾德 莫罗所说的..
..with what Ed Murrow has just said,..
..在这里为我和这个节目说
..and say I have never been prouder of CBS.
..我从未如此为CBS感到自豪
Senator McCarthy said today that he would demand equal free television....
参议员麦卡锡今日说道 他要求电视媒体平等地....
Stevenson had charged that the Senator made demagoguery and deceit..
斯蒂文森指责参议员（麦卡锡） 煽动和欺骗..
..the national policy....
..国家政策....
- Is that Hollenbeck?. - Congratulations!
- 那是霍伦贝克？ - 恭喜！
Great show!
好棒的节目！
Feel like a Scotch?
去喝一杯？
I think everybody could use a Scotch.
我想大伙都该去喝几杯
- It's 3:30, early editions are out. - I'm not worried about that.
- 凌晨3点半了，早报已经出来了 - 这我不担心
Of course not. Shirley, honey,..
当然不 雪莉，亲爱的..
..would you go across the street and get the early editions?
..帮忙到街对面取早报好吗？
- All of them? - Just get O'Brian!
- 都取来？ - 只拿奥布莱恩的好了
- Hey, watch my drink! - Yeah.
- 嘿，看好我的杯子 - 嗯
Okay. Here we go.
好了，来了
- At last! - The Times. - The Times...
- 总算来了！ - （纽约）时报
- First? - Good.
- 先读时报？ - 很好
- Who wrote it? - Jack Gould.
- 谁的文章？ - 杰克 古德
Gould...
古德...
Edward R. Murrow's television program on Senator Joseph R. McCarthy..
爱德华 R. 莫罗关于 参议员约瑟夫 R 麦卡锡的电视节目..
..was an exciting and provocative examination of the man and his methods.
..令人激动，并是对 此人此事挑战性的审视
It was crusading journalism of high responsibility and courage.
这是具有高度责任感和勇气 的新闻工作者的体现
For TV so often plagued by timidity and hesitation,..
在饱受胆怯和踯躅困扰的电视业
..the program was a milestone that reflected enlightened citizenship.
..这期节目堪比 具有公民启迪作用的里程碑
The program.... Hold on!
这期节目.... 等等！
The program was no less an indictment of those who wish..
这期节目对于那些 希望参议员的
..the problems posed by the Senator's tactics and theatrics..
..手段和效果所激起的事件 不了了之并漠不关心的人来讲
..would just go away and leave them alone.
..不啻于一种控诉
That was Mr. Murrow's and television's triumph,..
这是莫罗先生和电视业的胜利
..and a very great one.
..伟大的胜利
Here! Here!
举杯！举杯！
- He hated it. - Yeah. What's his beef?
- 他不喜欢 - 是呀，他抱怨什么？
Send the NewYorkTimes a bottle of Scotch.
给纽约时报送一瓶威士忌
I already did. How do you think we got that review?
早送过了，要不你以为 这评论是哪来的？
- How'sthe Post? - Pretty good!
- 邮报怎么说？ - 挺好的！
- What about O'Brian? - Uh, the same.
- 奥布莱恩呢？ - 唔，老样子
- Go on, read O'Brian! - I don't have it.
- 继续，念奥布莱恩的！ - 我没
- Got it. - Oh. Here.
- 有了 - 哦，在这
- There we go. - Shirley, that....
- 我来念了 - 雪莉，还是....
We can't saywe were surprised at Murrow's "Hate McCarthy" telecast..
当莫罗经过圆滑巧妙的编辑 从麦卡锡对共产分子斗争的…
..last evening, when his explosively one-sided propaganda,..
片段中选材制作的 片面的“憎恨麦卡锡”报道…
..edited with deviously clever selectivity from McCarthy's march..
在昨天播出后 紧接着好像老谋深算的…
..against Communism, was finished last evening..
安排那样 便是莫罗在PM（左派媒体）的…
..by equally Machiavellian coincidence the following telecast..
同门霍伦贝克的 电视节目
..featured Murrow's PM protg, Hollenbeck.
我们显然对此不必感到惊讶
In an obviously gloating mood, Hollenbeck..
以一种明显 沾沾自喜的神态
..hoped viewers had witnessed his patron's triumph..
..霍伦贝克希望观众见证 他的伙伴为左派..
..from and for the Left.
..所赢得的胜利
So on. So on...
等等，等等...
Shirley, it's okay. Go ahead, finish it.
雪莉，没关系 继续，读完
- No, that's it. That's it. - Shirley, please, finish it.
- 不，够了，够了 - 雪莉，没事，读完
The CBS has been in a lengthy "clean house of Lefties" mood.
CBS已经成了左派分子 “内部清洗”的模式
The worst offenders on lesser levels..
较低级别的反对者..
..have been quietly pushed out of the company.
..都已经被不动声色地 赶出了公司
Don Hollenbeck, a graduate of the demised pinko publication PM,..
唐 霍伦贝克，这个已消失的 左派出版物PM的门生
..attacked conservative papers with sly and slanted propaganda.
..以狡猾和歪曲的新闻报道 攻击保守媒体
He then proceeded through an equally..
接着他也继续的
..with McCarthy dominating his words, actions, attitudes.
..进行歪曲片面的报道和评论
So on.
就是这些
- It's O'Brian. - He didn't get the Scotch, that's all.
- 还是奥布莱恩罢了 - 他没收到威士忌，仅此而已
- Is it grammatically correct? - I'll have that cigarette, Ed.
- 语句通顺吗？ - 我要抽只烟，艾德
- Thanks, Shirley. - Oh. - Mmh. - Thankyou.
- 谢谢，雪莉 - 哦  - 谢谢
Joe... Shirley...
乔... 雪莉...
It doesn't matter.
没关系的
To Jack Gould!
敬杰克 古德！
- To Jack! To Jack! To Jack Gould! - To Jack Gould!
- 敬杰克！敬杰克！敬杰克 古德！ - 敬杰克 古德！
I love Jack Gould!
我喜欢杰克 古德！
May he rest in peace.
- 愿他安息 - 啥？
- Hello, Jimmy. - Fred, congratulations! - Thankyou.
- 你好，吉米 - 弗瑞德，恭喜！ - 谢谢
I got such a hangover to go along with the ulcer.
昨晚喝到难受
All the ad guys on the 3rd floor watched the show.
3楼广告部的同事 全都看了你的节目
Got a good review in the NewYork Times. Jack Gould.
纽约时报的评论不错，杰克 古德
We're putting out a press release..
我们要发的新闻稿..
..saying that calls came in 15 to 1 in favor of the show. - Really?
..会写道打进来赞成节目的比例是15比1 - 真的？
- Yeah. - 15 to 1? - We got calls from everywhere.
- 没错   - 15比1？ - 全国各地的电话
- East Coast or West Coast? - Yeah. Kansas City, Cincinnati....
- 东海岸还是西海岸？ - 没错，堪萨斯，辛辛纳提....
Mr. Paley...
佩利先生...
- Morning, Fred. - Morning, Mr. Paley.
- 早上好，弗瑞德 - 早上好，佩利先生
How's your wife?
你太太好吗？
She's fine. We're getting ready to move.
她很好，我们准备好搬家了
- Really? Where to? - Riverdale. We found a nice house there.
- 是吗？搬哪去？ - 河溪谷，那有座很好的房子
It's nice there.
那是不错
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Excuse me.
失陪
Fred! McCarthy wants William Buckley to do his rebuttal.
弗瑞德！麦卡锡要求威廉 巴克利 制作他的辩驳
I said no.
我拒绝了
Yes, sir.
是，先生
Hey, Johnny!
嗨，约翰尼！
- Radulovich has been reinstated. - What?!
- 瑞杜维奇已经复职了 - 什么？！
Radulovich.... Guys! Radulovich has been reinstated.
瑞杜维奇.... 伙计们！ 瑞杜维奇已经复职了
- Jesse! Jesse! - Where is Ed?
- 杰西！杰西！ - 艾德在哪？
- He's in the bullpen. Why? What's going on? - Jess!
- 他在大房间里，怎么？ 发生什么事了？ - 杰西！
Got some very good news.
有好消息
Special announcement from the Secretary of the Air Force!
特别声明 来自于空军部长！
Fellas! Listen up! Everyone!
大伙都听好了！
I have decided that it is consistent..
我已经决定 恢复瑞杜维奇中尉
..with the interests of the National Security to retain..
..在美国空军的职务 是完全符合
..Lieutenant Radulovich in the United StatesAir Force. Stop.
..国家安全需要的 等等
He is not, in my opinion, a security risk. Full stop.
依我看来，他并非危险分子 句号
There you go. Harold E. Talbott, Secretary from theAir Force.
署名，哈罗德 E 塔尔波特 空军部长
Great job!
干得好！
- Make a copy of that for me! - I will do, Fred!
- 帮我做个复本！ - 我会的，弗瑞德！
Back to work, guys! We got a lot of work to do.
接着工作，大伙！ 还有很多事要做
This means something.
这有意义的
- Good news, huh? - Congratulations!
- 好消息，嗯？ - 真好
- This absolutely means something. - Absolutely. This is the start of....
- 这绝对有意义 - 绝对，这是新....
Palmer!
帕默！
The CBS lawyers wanna talk to you.
CBS的律师要找你谈话
When?
什么时候？
Tomorrow.
明天
I don't want you to get paranoid, they're talking to everybody.
我不想你胡思乱想 他们找所有人谈话的
Any ideas?
有什么建议？
Just tell them what you know.
实话实说
- Now is that testimony true? - No, sir, it is not.
- 现在那段证词是真实的吗？ - 不，先生，不是
Not at any time have I been a member of the Communist Party..
我从未加入过共产党..
..and I have never seen a Communist card.
..并且我从未接触过 共产党宣传卡
- You've never seen a Communist card? - That's right.
- 你从未接触过共产党宣传卡？ - 是的
Have you ever attended any Communist meetings?
你参加过共产党集会吗？
No, sir, never.
不，先生，从未参加过
Have you ever subscribed to The Daily Worker?
你订阅过《每日工人报》吗？
No, sir. I didn't subscribe to it and I wouldn't pay for it.
没有，先生，我没有订阅过 并且也不会去买
Uh... Now, Mrs. Markward, who was working for the FBI,..
唔... 现在，为FBI工作的 马克沃德小姐..
..who joined the Communist Party under orders from the FBI,..
..受命加入共产党..
..has testified that while she never met you personally..
..作证说她从未共产分子集会上..
..at a Communist meeting that your name was on the list..
..见过你本人 但你的名字在
..of Communists who were paying dues.
..共产分子的应收帐款上
Uh... Can you shed any light upon that?
呃... 对此你有什么要说的吗？
No, sir. I don't even know what the dues are..
不，先生，我根本不知道 应收帐款是什么..
..or where they were paid. - So you have never paid any money..
..也不知道上哪去付 - 那么你从未付钱给..
..to the Communist Party.
..共产党
- Is that correct? - That's right.
- 是这样吗？ - 是的
You've never paid any dues, payment....
你从未付过....
Thank you very much, Leo!
非常感谢，里奥！
Good work, Joe, Charlie.
干得好，乔，查理
Now what is the show?
现在，节目讲什么？
Is it defending Annie Lee Moss as not being a Communist?
是为安妮 李 摩斯 并非共产分子而辩护？
- Or is it her Constitutional rights? - Both. - The latter.
- 还是为她的公民权？ - 两者 - 后者
We're much better sticking out the Constitutional issues.
我们最好盯住宪法条款这一块
- Agreed? - The woman is not a Communist spy.
- 同意吗？ - 这女人不是共产党的间谍
Joe McCarthy said that they have a spy in the Pentagon,..
麦卡锡说共党在五角大楼有间谍..
..that spy has gotten into the code room,..
..而且那间谍打入了密码室
..and that that spy is Annie Lee Moss.
..就是安妮 李 摩斯
I've got NewYorkTimes reports. McCarthy asserts he has..
我拿到了纽约时报的报道 麦卡锡声称他掌握了..
..a new red link toArmy. Quote, "Senator McCarthy charged today.."
..通往军队的赤色环节，引语 “参议员麦卡锡今天指责道…”
"..that the Army now employs a woman in its code room.."
“目前军方雇佣曾是或者仍旧是…”
"..who was, and still may be, an active Communist."
“共产分子的一个妇女 在他们的密码室工作”
It's the front page of the New YorkTimes.
纽约时报的头版报道的
No sooner is he done chastising the other committee members for wanting..
然后他责难完 另外想把事情推到…
..to push into the afternoon, than what? Seven questions in,..
..下午的委员后 接着呢？7个问题过后
..he ducks out, leaves.... - Right.
..他就闪人了，离开了 - 没错
- He leaves. - It's all over the headlines, all over the country.
- 他离开了 - 每个头版都是，全国都是这报道
Get me copies from any newspaper..
给我任何关于报道了..
..that printed anything about that assertion.
..那份声明的报纸
That's a good idea. You should get the Cincinnati Inquirer.
好主意，你该去找找辛辛纳提调查者报
- Chicago. - Couple other pieces I think we should include.
- 芝加哥  - 其他一些篇幅 我想他们也有报道
The fact that there's 3Annie Lee Moss's in the phone book.
事实上电话薄里有3个安妮 李 摩斯
There are 2 Robert Halls, one's colored, one's white.
2个罗伯特 豪斯 1个是有色人种，另一个是白人
We have some footage of the empty chair.
我们有些那张空椅子的特写画面
I think that says it all. Just that picture of McCarthy not....
我想那说明了问题 就是那关于在7个问题之后
McCarthy leaving the hearing after 7 questions..
麦卡锡离开听证会的画面..
..and then we'll cut to the shot of the chair.
..我们接着把剪辑画面 切到空椅子上
- We gotta do something about it. - All right, so....
- 我们就这么做好了 - 好的，那么....
Excuse me. Mr. Murrow! McCarthy wantsApril 6th.
打扰一下，大伙，莫罗先生！ 麦卡锡把时间定在4月6号
Thank you, Natalie.
谢谢，娜塔莉
Fine. If Charlie shoots it, we get to see it first. We should offer.
好，如果查理拍过了，我们就先看看 我们应该用那画面
- It's a long shot. - What the hell could McCarthy do?
- 那是个长镜头 - 麦卡锡能怎么办？？
Is he gonna debate himself? We just used his words!
自己和自己争辩？ 我们全都是引用他自己的话！
Johnny! Johnny! We know what it's going to be.
约翰尼！约翰尼！我们知道 他会反击的
He's going to come after me. There's nothing more he can do.
他会来针对我的 此外，他还能做什么
He's gonna bet that a Senator trumps a newsman.
他想赌一赌 参议员能击败新闻记者
He'll lose.
他会输的
Not if we're playing bridge.
若是打桥牌 他就不会输了
- I'm sorry, guys. I didn't mean to interrupt. - Hey, Don.
- 抱歉，大伙，我本不想打搅你们 - 嗨，唐
- It's getting fun now! - Ed, you have a minute?
- 越来越有趣了！ - 艾德，有空吗？
- Yes, I'll be right there. - All right, boys. Playtime's over.
- 好的，马上就来 - 好了，伙计们，游戏结束
We have 4 days..
我们有4天时间..
..to do a 28 minute show. - Yeah. - All right.
..去准备28分钟的节目 - 好 - 好的
All right, go ahead. Hi, Mary.
好的，加油干 嗨，玛丽
Hello, Mr. Hollenbeck. Mr. Murrow...
你好，霍伦贝克先生 莫罗先生...
- Could you give us a moment? - Sure.
- 让我们单独谈谈好吗？ - 好的
Thank you, dear.
谢谢，亲爱的
I have to ask you something, Ed. It's about O'Brian.
我有事相求，艾德 是关于奥布莱恩的
- O'Brian doesn't matter. - He's killing me, Ed.
- 奥布莱恩无足轻重 - 他让我焦头烂额，艾德
He doesn't amount to that much in the newsroom.
在新闻界他并非举足轻重
We've got to let that guy have it.
我们得让那家伙尝尝厉害
We're not going after O'Brian. I will not take on McCarthy and Hearst.
我们还不能对付奥布莱恩，我不想 同时与麦卡锡和赫斯特（奥布莱恩后台老板）交手
I can't defeat them both.
我不能同时击败他俩
Just don't read the papers. Or don't read O'Brian, anyway.
别读报纸了 要么别读他的文章
Okay. I guess not.
那好，就这样吧
Sorry, Don.
抱歉，唐
Although Mrs. Moss offered to testify,..
虽然摩斯女士愿意作证..
..Senator McCarthy suggested that she was too sick.
..参议员麦卡锡认为 她的病情太严重了
- She agreed.... - Mr. Cohn wanted to know about Mrs. Moss's connection....
- 她同意了.... - 科恩想知道关于摩斯女士与....
....to tell the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth,..
....说出事实，全部事实 以及只说事实..
..so help you God?
..愿主保佑你
May we get your full name for the record, please?
请说出你的全名以记录
Annie Lee Moss.
安妮 李 摩斯
- M-O-S-S? - That's right.
- M-O-S-S？ - 是的
Mrs. Moss, let me say for the record, for your information,..
作为备案来说 根据你的资料
..for the information of your counsel,..
..和你的律师提供的信息
..that you are not here because..
..你今天来这里，并非是由于
..you are considered important in the Communist apparatus.
..你是一个重要的共产党帮凶
We have the testimony that you are, and have been, a Communist.
我们有证词，证明你曾是 并且仍旧是共产党员
We are rather curious, however, to know how you suddenly..
而且我们非常地好奇 你究竟是如何
..were shifted from..
..突然间从..
..a worker in a cafeteria to the code room.
..餐厅招待进入密码室工作的
I am today much more interested..
今天在处理你的案子时
..in the handling of your case..
..更加引起我注意的
..by your superiors than in your own personal activities.
..并非你本人的活动 而是你的上级
However, counsel will question you about your own activities also.
当然，委员会也会就你 本人的活动进行质询
- Mr. Chairman! - We will not hear from counsel.
- 主席先生！ - 我们不会理睬律师
You have been told what the rule is.
你知道这里的规则
If you have anything to say, say it through your client.
如果你有话要说 请通过你的当事人去说
Chairman. Did you begin work at the General Accounting Office in..
在1945年你开始在 总审计局的办公室..
..1 945? - Yes, sir.
..工作？ - 是的，先生
And, prior to that time, had you been a cafeteria worker?
并且，在此之前 你曾是个自助餐厅招待？
Yes, I had.
是的，没错
I see. While in the Pentagon, since 1 950,..
我明白了，在五角大楼 自从1950年..
..have you had any connections with coded messages?
..你是否进行任何牵涉到 电码情报的处理工作？
Have you ever handled coded messages?
你是否曾处理过电码情报？
- No more than to transmit 'em. - Pardon me?
- 我只是转达情报 - 你说什么？
No more than to transmit the message.
我只是转送情报
Than to transmit them? Did you transmit codes?
转达？你只是转送情报？
To receive or transmit messages was all I had to do.
接收或转送情报 便是我全部的工作
And I've never been into a courtroom in my life.
并且我从未上过法庭
Do you know the..
你知道..
..type of classification....
..机密的分级....
- Do you know if they were secret, top secret, confidential? - No, sir.
- 你知道那些情报分秘密 绝密，机密吗？ - 不，先生
- You wouldn't know the degree of classification? - No, sir.
- 你不知道秘密的分级？ - 我不知道
I see.
我明白了
I'm afraid I'm going to have to excuse myself, I've got..
恐怕我得失陪了 我有..
..a rather important appointment to workon right now..
..重要的事情需要立刻处理
..and I wonder if, Senator Mundt, you would take over as Chairman?
..我想，参议员穆特 你来接手主席的工作好吗？
- Chairman. Uh... - Cohn.
- 主席先生，呃... - 科恩
I have no further questions of this witness at this time.
我现在没有其他问题了
We have the testimony of Mrs. Markward, the undercover agent for the FBI,..
我们有马克沃德小姐 一位FBI卧底探员的证词
..stating thatAnnie Lee Moss was a member, a dues-paying member..
..她证明安妮 李 摩斯曾是 一个共产党团体…
..of the Communist Party,..
..东北俱乐部..
..the Northeast Club of the Communist Party.
..的成员，也是缴费的成员
We have corroboration of that testimony by another..
在此听证会之前 我们也召集了
..witness who was called before the Committee..
..另一个证人提供确凿的证词
..and gave a sworn statement to the effect..
..并且她给出誓词以证明
..that she also knew Mrs. Moss as a member..
..她也知道摩斯小姐是..
..of the Northeast Club of the Communist Party.
..那个共产党团体 东北俱乐部的成员
She's already lost her job. She's been suspended because of this action.
她已经丢了工作 因为调查，她被剥夺了权利
I'm not defending her. If she's a Communist, I want her exposed.
我并不是在为她辩解，如果她是 共产分子，我愿意看到她被曝光
But to make these statements as we've got corroborating evidence..
但是既然我们已经有了 确凿的证据…
..that she is a Communist, under these circumstances,..
..来证明她是共产分子 在此条件下
..I thinkshe's entitled to have it produced here in her presence..
..我认为她有权 在她出席的情况下
..and let the public know about it and let her know about it.
..让公众，且让她知道 这些所谓的证据
I don't like to try people by hearsay evidence.
我不希望以道听途说 来进行审问
I'd like to get the witnesses here and try them..
我希望证人就站在这里 询问他们
..by testimony, under oath.
..让他们起誓，进行作证
The Chair will rule that the comment of Mr. Cohn..
主席团责成 科恩先生的陈述…
..be stricken from the record.
..必须严格基于记录
I didn't ask that, Mr. Chairman!
这并非我要求的，主席先生！
....whether we should try to produce a witness in public..
....是否让证人出席作证…
..because the FBI may have her undercover and we don't want to....
..是由于FBI可能派她进行卧底 并且我们不想…
You can't strike these statements made by counsel here as to evidence..
你不能用持有 但扣交的证据来反击
..that we're having and withholding. You cannot strike that from the press..
..律师做出的陈述 一旦造成这样的后果
..nor from the public mind once it's planted there. That's the..
你从媒体以及大众的思想上 都是抹不掉的，那是
..evil of it!
..一种诽谤！
- Well, I'd look at it.... - I don't think it's fair to a witness,..
- 我考虑的是… - 我认为这很不公平…
..to a citizen of this country,..
..对于证人，对于这个国家的公民..
..to bring them up here and cross-examine them,..
..把他们带来 并且反复盘问
..then when they get through, say,..
..接着等他们熬完了，说
.."The FBI has got something on you that condemns you."
..“FBI掌握了一些证据 能判你的刑”
- The Chair agrees.... - It is not sworn testimony,..
- 主席团同意.... - 这不是宣誓的证词..
..it's convicting people by rumor and hearsay and innuendo.
..这是以道听途说、含沙射影 来给人治罪
You will notice that neither Senator McClellan or Senator Symington..
您可以注意到 不论参议员麦克莱伦，还是参议员塞明顿
..nor this reporter know or claim that Mrs. Moss was or is a Communist.
..还是这个记者都不知道或者没有断言 摩斯小姐曾是或者还是共产分子
They simply claimed that she had the right to meet her accusers face to face.
他们只是声称她有权 与原告面对面
One month ago tonight we presented a report on Senator Joseph R. McCarthy.
一个月以前，我们播出了 一部关于参议员约瑟夫 R. 麦卡锡的节目
We labeled it as controversial.
我们将节目看做是富有争议的
Most of that report consisted of words and pictures of the Senator.
节目的许多解说词和画面 都是关于参议员的
At that time, we said,..
那时，我们就说…
.."If the Senator believes we have done violence to his words or pictures,.."
如果参议员认为我们的节目 歪曲了他的讲话、形象..
"..if he desires to speak, to answer himself,.."
并且他要为自己申辩..
"..an opportunity would be afforded him on this program."
我们欢迎他上我们的节目
The Senator sought the opportunity after 3 weeks..
3周过去了，参议员 终于有了机会..
..because he was very busy and wished adequate time to prepare his reply.
..因为他非常繁忙，并想 抽出足够的时间来准备答复
We agreed.
我们同意了
We placed no restrictions on the manner of the presentation of his reply..
我们对他的答复形式 不做任何约束..
..and we suggested that we would not take time to comment..
..并且我们也不会在 他的节目时间里面
..on this particular program.
..予以评论和反驳
Here now is Senator Joseph R. McCarthy, junior Senator from Wisconsin.
下面的时间交给参议员约瑟夫 R. 麦卡锡 威斯康星州下级参议员
Good evening. Mr. Edward R. Murrow, Educational Director of the CBS,..
诸位晚上好，爱德华 R. 莫罗先生 CBS的主管们..
..devoted his program to an attack..
..致力于制作播出 攻击美国参议院调查委员会
..on the work of the US Senate Investigating Committee,..
..以及作为主席的我本人
..and on me personally as its Chairman.
..的电视节目
Now, over the past 4 years, he has made repeated attacks upon me..
在过去的四年里 他再三地对我和…
..and those fighting Communists.
..反共斗士进行攻击
Of course, neither Joe McCarthy nor Edward R. Murrow..
当然，无论乔 麦卡锡 还是爱德华 R. 莫罗..
..is of any great importance as individuals.
..都不是什么举足轻重的人物
We are only important..
我们的价值仅仅…
..in our relation to the great struggle to preserve our American liberties.
..在于我们投身到捍卫美国自由 的伟大斗争中去
Now ordinarily, I wouldn't take time out from the important work at hand..
一般来讲，一般来讲 我是不会从繁忙的工作中抽出时间
..to answer Murrow.
..去回应莫罗
However, in this case,..
然而，到现在..
..I feel justified in doing so because Murrow is the symbol,..
..我认为有必要进行反击 是因为莫罗是象征
..the leader..
..领导..
..and the cleverest of the jackal pack which is always found at the throat..
..也是最狡猾的走狗 藏匿在敢于揭发
..of anyone who dares to expose individual Communists and traitors.
..共产分子和叛徒的人们中间
And I am compelled by the fact,..
事实使得我来告诉你们
..to say to you that Mr. Edward R. Murrow,..
..一些关于爱德华 R. 莫罗先生的事情
..as far back as 20 years ago,..
..在20年之前
..was engaged in propaganda for Communist causes.
..他从事共产主义性质的宣传活动
For example, the Institute of International Education,..
例如，他受苏联情报机关 委派担任
..of which he was theActing Director,..
..国际教育学院的
..was chosen to act as a representative..
..执行总裁
..by a Soviet agency..
..去从事
..to do a job which would normally be done by the Russian secret police.
..通常由苏联秘密警察完成的工作
Mr. Murrow, by his own admission, was a member of the IWW,..
莫罗先生，他自己承认 也是IWW
..that's the Industrial Workers of the World,..
..也就是世界产业工人组织
..a terrorist organization cited as subversive..
..这个被司法部定为
..by an Attorney General of the United States.
..恐怖颠覆组织的成员
Mr. Murrow said on this program and I quote,..
我来引用莫罗先生 在节目中说过的话
.."The actions of the junior Senator from Wisconsin.."
..“这位来自威斯康星州 的下级参议员的行为”
"..have given considerable comfort to the enemy."
“已经让敌人感到快意”
That is the language of our statute of treason, rather strong language.
这样的话语是对我们政令 的背叛，也是相当强硬的措辞
If I am giving comfort to our enemies, I ought not to be in the Senate.
如果我让我们的敌人感到快意 我就不应该留在参议院
If, on the other hand, Mr. Murrow..
反之，另一方面 莫罗先生..
..is giving comfort to our enemies,..
..如果让敌人感到快意
..he ought not to be brought into the homes..
..那么他也不该留在 让他得以面对..
..of millions of Americans by the CBS.
..上百万美国家庭的CBS
And I want to assure you..
在此我向你们保证
..that I will not be deterred..
..我决不会因
..by the attacks of the Murrows, the Lattimores, the Fosters,..
..莫罗，拉蒂摩尔，福斯特
..The Daily Worker or the Communist Party itself.
..每日工人报或共产党 的攻击而动摇
And I make no claim to leadership.
而且我并没有 任何要夺权的意图
In complete humility..
我诚挚地期望
..I do ask you and every American who loves this country..
..我期望你们以及 每一个热爱美国的民众
..to join with me.
..加入到我的行列中来
[Everyone talks about the weather]
[人人都关心天气]
[Wherever you look on America's modern farms,.]
[无论你造访美国哪处 现代化的农场]
[..aluminum is on the job, helping the farmer do something about the weather]
[..铝合金都在发挥着作用 帮助农民们改善天气的影响]
[Aluminum for the farm is one more example of how Alcoa,.]
[铝合金在农业上的应用 也是始于1888年的]
[..since 1888,..]
[..Alco公司]
[..has continued to pioneer new uses for this vital metal]
[..持续她在这一重要金属 应用上的领先地位]
[New uses of aluminum that mean better farms and better farming]
[铝合金的新应用意味着 更先进的农场和农业]
[The aluminum from the nation's first and leading producer,.]
[全国首创与领先的 铝行业企业]
[..Alcoa, Aluminum Company of America]
[..Alcoa 美国铝合金公司]
Last week, Senator McCarthy appeared on this program..
上周，参议员麦卡锡 参与到我们的节目..
..to correct any errors he might have thought we made..
..以纠正他以为 我们在3月9日的节目中
..in our report of March 9th.
..可能出现过的一些错漏
Since he made no reference to any statements of fact that we made,..
由于对我们的节目 他没有举出任何证明
..we must conclude that he found no errors of fact.
..因此我们的结论是 他没有找出任何错误
He proved again that anyone who exposes him,..
再一次地，他证明了
..anyone who doesn't share his disregard for decency and human dignity..
..任何揭露他，反对他
..and the rights guaranteed by the Constitution..
..对宪法赋予的人权 进行蔑视和践踏
..must be either a Communist or a fellow traveler.
..的人士不是共产分子 就是亲共分子
I fully expected this treatment.
我完全料想到了他的反应
The Senator added this reporter's name to a long list of individuals..
参议员并将这位记者的名字 同一长串他已经指责过的
..and institutions he has accused of serving the Communist cause.
..共产主义个人和组织 联系在一起
His proposition is very simple:
他的意图很简单
..anyone who criticizes or opposes Senator McCarthy's methods..
..任何指责或者反对 参议员麦卡锡议案的人
..must be a Communist.
..肯定就是共产分子
And if that be true, there are an awful lot of Communists in the USA.
若那是真实的 那美国的共产分子真是不计其数了
For the record, let's consider briefly some of the Senator's charges.
其次，让我们来简要 分析一下参议员的指控
He claimed, but offered no proof,..
他声称，可从未证明
..that I had been a member of the Industrial Workers of the World.
..我一直是世界产业工盟的成员
That is false.
这是错误的
I was never a member of the IWW, never applied for membership.
我从未加入过IWW 也从未申请加入过
The Senator charged that Professor Harold Laski,..
参议员指责哈罗德 拉斯基教授..
..a British scholar and politician, dedicated a book to me.
..一位英国学者和政治家 题献一本书给我过
That's true.
这是真实的
He is dead. He was a socialist, I am not.
他去世了 他是社会主义者，可我不是
He was a civilized individual..
他是一位谦逊有礼..
..who did not insist upon agreement with his political principles..
..且从不会将自己的政治信仰 作为交流和友好的前提..
..as a pre-condition for conversation or friendship.
..而强加给别人的绅士
I do not agree with his political ideas.
我并不赞同他的 政治主张
Laski, as he makes clear in the introduction,..
拉斯基，正如他在 他的序言里面写道的..
..dedicated the book to me, not because of political agreement,..
并非出于政见相同 而是因为对…
..but because he held my wartime broadcast from London in high regard.
..我在战时广播贡献的高度赞扬 而将作品题献给我
And the dedication so reads.
这在致辞上可以读到
I believed 20 years ago and I believe today..
20年来我始终坚信
..that mature Americans can engage in conversation and controversy,..
..成熟理性的美国人 在任何地方
..the clash of ideas, with Communists anywhere in the world..
..与共产主义者的 碰撞和交流中
..without becoming contaminated or converted.
..都不会被污染或同化
I believe that our faith, our conviction,..
我相信我们的信仰 我们的信念..
..our determination are stronger than theirs..
..我们的决心 同他们（共产主义者）一样坚定
..and that we can successfully compete, not only in the area of bombs,..
..且不论是军事上 还是思想上，我们都可以
..but in the area of ideas.
..与他们竞争
I have worked with CBS for more than 19 years.
我为CBS工作已经 超过19个年头了
The company has subscribed fully to my integrity and responsibility..
不论是作为一个正直有责任感的 新闻工作者，还是一个忠诚的美国公民
..as a broadcaster and as a loyal American.
..CBS对此从不感到怀疑
I require no lectures from the junior Senator from Wisconsin..
至于共产主义的危险或恐怖
..as to the dangers or terrors of Communism.
..我不需要一个来自 威斯康星州下级参议员的说教
Having searched my conscience and my files,..
探究过我的良心 与我的经历
..I cannot contend that I have always been right or wise,..
..我不确定自己是否一直 是正确或明智的
..but I have attempted to pursue the truth with diligence..
..但我始终勤勉努力地 探求真相
..and to report it,..
..并报道真相..
..even though, as in this case, I had been warned in advance..
..即便，在这个节目制作之前 我已经被事先劝告过
..that I would be subjected to the attentions of Senator McCarthy.
..我将会引起 参议员麦卡锡的注意
We shall hope to deal with matters of more vital interest next week.
希望我们下周的节目 能专注到更重要的时事中去
Good night, and good luck.
祝您晚安，好运
In the last analysis, the Senator was perched on the television high dive..
归根到底，参议员是在 电视节目上表演高台跳水
..and all prepared to make a resounding splash.
..准备好来个惊世一跳
He jumped beautifully, but he neglected to check first..
他动作优美 可惜忘记先检查
..where he was going to land. It must have been a shock..
..落水点了 当他发现莫罗先生已经
..to discover that Mr. Murrow had drained the water out of the pool.
..把池子的水排干 他一定非常震惊
- Is that the Times? Gould? - Yeah, it's Jack Gould.
- 纽约时报？古德？ - 是的，杰克 古德
- He's a hell of a writer. - Yes, he is.
- 他可是个厉害的写手 - 没错
- If we can afford him! - Stanton's got a public opinion....
- 要能请的起他就好了！ - 斯坦顿那里有民意…
Senate's investigating McCarthy.
参议院在调查麦卡锡
What?
什么？
TheArmy's charging that McCarthy and Cohn exercised undue pressure..
军方指责麦卡锡与科恩 实施不适当的压力
..to get preferential treatment for Schine. - Who's the source?
..来为席尼（其高级助手） 谋得特别待遇    - 哪来得消息？
- Got a second source? - There isn't, but this is coming out in 2 hours.
- 还有其他的来源吗？ - 没了，可这是2小时内的消息了
- Who's heading up the investigation? - It's not gonna be McCarthy!
- 谁负责调查？ - 不可能还是麦卡锡！
- Really? - What happened?
- 真的？ - 怎么了？
- Also get me the Washington Post! - What's going on?
- 把华盛顿邮报给我！ - 这是怎么了？
It's Williams for Jack Thompson.
威廉姆斯找杰克 汤姆森
The Senate's investigating McCarthy.
参议院开始调查麦卡锡
There is an added bit of comedy to this whole story.
现在整个事情变得幽默起来了
The Committee cannot convene for several days..
由于参议员麦卡锡轻微的咽喉炎
..because Senator McCarthy has a slight case of laryngitis.
..委员会将暂停几日召集
And he must recover over the desert air of Arizona.
并要等他从亚利桑那的 干燥气候中复原过来
- But Stevens is going after him and it looks like Joe Welch. - Yeah.
- 可斯蒂文斯在追查他 似乎还有乔 韦尔奇    - 是呀
They're gonna allow each side to call witnesses..
他们会让各派传召证人
..and be privy to other testimony.
..而且还不透露证词
- Fred, we still have a meeting! - We're gonna go to talk to Thompson.
- 弗瑞德，我们还有会议！ - 我们要和汤普森谈谈
No, thanks, Jack. Bye.
不，谢了，杰克，再见
Freddy, we're a hit. Right up there with "Howdy Dowdy"!
弗瑞迪，我们成功了 与“你好杜迪”（当时一成功电视节目） 有的一比！
The fact of newscaster Don Hollenbeck's suicide yesterday..
新闻播音员唐 霍伦贝克 于昨日自杀的消息
..does not remove from the record that peculiar history..
..并未抵消CBS一贯纵容
..of the leftist slanting of news indulged consistently by the CBS.
..由左派进行歪曲新闻报道的事实
Hollenbeck was what most astute students of CBS's strange..
霍伦贝克是CBS奇特、可疑的..
..and questionable new methods considered..
新方法的最狡猾的学生
.."typical of its newscasters". By Jack O'Brian.
并被认做是其“典型新闻播音员” 笔者杰克 奥布莱恩
Oh, yeah. I like it like that.
哦，这样很好
One of the best programs I ever heard was called "CBS Views The Press".
我所知道的最好的 一个节目叫做“CBS读报”
A great many people liked it, some didn't,..
很多人都喜欢 而有的不..
..but no one ever called it anything but honest.
..可没人会否认节目的诚实！
It was the workof an honest reporter. Don Hollenbeck.
它也是一位诚实的记者 唐 霍伦贝克的结晶
He also worked occasionally on "See It Now".
他有时也会客串“即时观察”
He did the 11 p.m. news over some of these stations.
他为电视台播报晚间11时新闻
He had been sick lately and he died this morning.
最近他饱受病痛的折磨 并于今早去世
The police said it was suicide... gas.
警方结论死于自杀…煤气中毒
Not much of an obit.
这并非讣告
But, at least we got our facts straight, and it was brief.
可，至少我们知道了真相 简明扼要的真相
And that's all Don Hollenbeck would have asked.
而这就是唐 霍伦贝克 一生所追求的
Good night, and good luck.
祝您晚安，好运
Got to be in Philadelphia this morning.
今早要去费城
What time is your train?
几点的车？
8:00.
8:00
- Charlie going with you? - Uh-huh.
- 查理和你一道？ - 嗯
Here's a thought.
我在想
What if we're wrong?
要是我们错了怎么办？
We're not wrong.
我们没错
We're not going to look back..
我们不能走回头路..
..and saywe protected the wrong side?
..并说我们保护了错的一边
Protected them from what? In the name of what? What would we be preserving?
保护他们什么？以什么名义？ 我们会留下什么？
Argument could be made, "for the greater good".
总会有争执 “为了更多人的福祉”
Not once you give it all away. It's no good then.
除非你放弃，就不会有争执了 那样也不好
It's just a thought.
只是想想
Senator, may we not drop this? We know he belonged to the Lawyer's Guild.
参议员，我们不必讨论这个 我们知道你是律师协会的
And Mr. Cohn nods his head at me.
并且科恩朝我点头了
- I did you, I think, no personal injury, Mr. Cohn. - No, sir.
- 我想，我并未对你人身伤害 - 没有，先生
- I meant to do you no personal injury. - No.
- 我也无意对你人身伤害 - 没有
And if I did, I beg your pardon.
若我伤害你了 请求你的原谅
Let us not assassinate this lad further, Senator. You've done enough.
让我们不要再诋毁这个年轻人了 参议员，你做的够多了
- Let's... let's.... - Have you no sense of decency, sir?
- 我们... 我们.... - 你还有一点点庄重感吗？先生
At long last, have you left no sense of decency?
到最后，你还有没有 一点庄重感？
- I know this hurts you, Mr. Welch. - Senator, I think it hurts you, too.
- 我知道这伤害了你，韦尔奇先生 - 参议员，我认为这也同样伤害了你
- I'd like to finish this. - Have you some private reservation..
- 请让我说完 - 当你宣誓说出全部事实
..when you take the oath that you will tell the whole truth..
..而使得你有权去 审理你要证实的事情
..that lets you be the judge of what you will testify to?
..你是不是还私下有所保留？
The answer is there's no reservation about telling the whole truth.
我的回答是 对事实我没有任何保留
Thank you, sir. Then tell us who delivered the documents to you!
谢谢你，先生，那么请回答我们 文档是谁交给你的！！
I don't want to mean that this new fashion is not chic.
我的意思是这一款式 并非不太别致
- I think it's just no good for me. - Uh, not for you.
- 我想只是不合我而已 - 阿，对你不太合适
Milko, anything you care to say on that subject?
米尔库，对此你有什么想说的？
I think no comment.
我不予置评
It's got to be there. If you can't find it, I can't write about it.
在这会很好，如果你找不到 我也没法去写
- Check again. - Charlie said he dropped it off.
- 再找找 - 查理说他就放这的
- Charlie said he dropped.... - Shirley, can I see you a minute?
- 查理说他放.... - 雪莉，现在有空吗？
- I got to call you back. - Joe!
- 我待会打给你 - 乔！
You, too.
你也来
Close the door.
把门关上
Have a seat.
请坐
- How are you? - Fine, thank you. - Swell. Yeah.
- 最近好吗？ - 很好，谢谢  - 挺好的，嗯
Uh, you both are aware that there's a policy at CBS..
呃，你们都清楚 CBS的规章..
..that no two employees can be married.
..雇员之间是不能结婚的
I want to ask you a question, but I don't want you to answer it.
我有个问题要问 而不用你们回答
I want you to consider it.
我要你们想想
I know you two are married.
我知道你俩结婚了
Everyone knows.
大家都知道
That's not my question.
这不是我的问题
In the next few weeks I have to lay off a couple of people.
接下来的几周 我不得不进行裁员
We're making some significant cuts across the board.
我们要在各部门进行削减
I wanted you to know that,..
我让你俩知道
..because you could save someone else being fired.
..是因为可以为别人 省下一个名额
I'm asking you to consider making this decision a little easier.
我要你们考虑一下 这样更容易做出选择
I don't need an answer now.
现在不必答复我
Just think about it.
考虑一下
Good.
很好
- Well, Joe... - Well?
- 那么，乔... - 那么
- Sure we're gonna miss you around here. - I'll pack my things.
- 我们会想你的 - 我会去收拾东西的
- I think it's for the best. - We'll find out!
- 我想这样最好 - 走着瞧
Mrs. Wershba...
沃什太太...
Everybody knew.
大家都知道
Natalie, did he say what it was about?
娜塔莉，他说是关于什么的？
No. Just that he wanted to talk to you in his office.
没，只是找你去他办公室谈
Uh-oh!
啊哦！
The problem isn't simply that you've lost your sponsor.
问题不仅仅是 你丢了赞助商
With Alcoa, "See It Now" still loses money.
即便Alcoa还在，“即时观察” 还是赔钱的
The fee is 50,000 dollars.
赔了5万美元
Last week's episode we did for less than 50,000 dollars.
我们上周节目的亏空 在5万美元以下
Fred, you're speaking beyond your competence.
弗瑞德，现在轮不到你说话
We'll certainly find another sponsor.
我们会找到另外的赞助商的
"64,000 Dollar Question" brings in over 80,000 in sponsors..
“64000美元问答”吸引了 8万美元的赞助..
..and it costs one-third of what you do.
..而制作成本 仅仅是你们的1/3
Ed, I've got Tuesday night programming that's number one.
艾德，我已有周二晚间档的节目规划 那是最重要的
People want to enjoy themselves. They don't want a civics lesson.
大众只是要娱乐 而不是公民课
- What do you want, Bill? - I don't want to get a stomachache..
- 那你要什么？比尔 - 我不要每次你弄个争议话题…
..every time you take on a controversial subject.
搅得我胃痛
I'm afraid that's the price you have to be willing to pay.
恐怕这是你必须乐意 去付的代价
Let's walk very carefully through these next few moments.
接下来我们都必须 处处留神
The content of what we're doing is more important..
我们在做的节目..
..than what some guy in Cincinnati.... - It's what you're doing, Ed. Not me.
..要比那些辛辛纳提的家伙重要的多.... - 那是你要做得，艾德，不是我
Not Frank Stanton. You.
也不是弗兰克 斯坦顿，是你
"CBS News", "See It Now" all belong toyou, Bill.
“CBS新闻”，“即时观察” 都规你名下，比尔
You wouldn't know it.
没那么简单
- What is ityou want? Credit? - I never censored a single program.
- 你要什么？信任？ - 我从不审查你们的节目
I hold on to affiliates whowanted entertainment from us.
我坚持吸引那些希望从CBS 得到娱乐的观众
I fight to keep the license..
我为保住执照而..
..with the very same politicians that you are bringing down,..
..与那些你正抨击的政客斗争
..and I never, never said no to you. Never.
..并且我从未，从未 对你说不，从未
I would argue that we have done very well by one another.
我会争辩道我们 彼此做的都很出色
I would argue that this network..
我会争辩道这个广播网的价值..
..is defined by what the news department has accomplished.
..取决于新闻部的成就
And I would also argue that never saying no is not the same as not censoring.
并且我会争辩道从不说不 并不等同于不去审查节目
Really? You should teach journalism. You and Mr. Friendly.
是吗？那你该去教新闻学 你和弗莱德利先生
Let me ask you this:
我来问你一个问题：
..why didn't you correct McCarthy..
..当麦卡锡声称 阿吉 希斯是叛国罪
..when he said that Alger Hiss was convicted of treason?
为什么你不指出错误？
He was only convicted of perjury. You corrected everything else.
他只是作伪证而已 其他所有的错误你都指出了
Did you not want the appearance of defending a known Communist?
你是不想让人觉得你是在为 一个已知的共产分子辩护吧？
I would argue that everyone censors, including you.
我会争辩道每个人 都会去审视，包括你
What do you want to do, Bill?
你要怎么样？比尔
I'm taking your program from a half an hour to an hour.
我要把你的节目 从半小时放到一小时长
And it won't be a weekly program and it won't be Tuesday nights.
并且不再是每周一期的节目 也不再是周二晚
- When would it be? - Sunday afternoons.
- 那是什么时候？ - 周日下午
- How many episodes? - 5.
- 一共几集？ - 5
Why don't you just fire me, Bill?
为什么不直接炒了我？比尔
I don't think it's what either of us wants.
这是我们都不愿看到的
You owe me 5 shows.
你还欠我5期节目
- You won't like the subject matter. - Probably not.
- 你不会喜欢我做的节目的 - 可能是的
Fred, I'll need you for a moment.
弗瑞德，你再留一会
- Thank you, Mary. - Goodbye, Mr. Friendly.
- 谢谢你， - 再见，弗莱德利先生
- He wants me to lay a few people off. - I'm sure he does.
- 他要我裁些人 - 我就知道会这样
Let's do our first show about the downfall of television.
让我们做一期关于 电视业衰败的节目
- Senate's gonna vote to censure McCarthy tomorrow. - Probably.
- 明天参议院将投票谴责麦卡锡 - 或许
- And then what happens? - He sits in the back row. - Right.
- 然后接下来呢？ - 他退到后排去了  - 没错
- They keep him in the Senate. They don't kick him out. - No, he stays.
- 他们还把他留在参议院 不把他踢出去   - 是的，他还待着
Well, we might as well go down swinging.
那么，我们最好体面地下台
Did you know the most trusted man in America is Milton Berle?
你知道在美国最受信赖 的人是米尔顿 伯利（著名喜剧演员）吗？
See, you should have worn a dress!
瞧，你该衣冠华丽！
- How does a Scotch sound? - Scotch sounds good.
- 去喝杯如何？ - 乐意至极
- Did you know Joe and Shirley were married? - Sure.
- 你知道乔和雪莉结婚了？ - 当然
- Did everyone know? - Pretty much.
- 大家都知道？ - 显然
We are proud because from the beginning of this nation..
我们自豪，是因为 自这个国家建立初期
..man can walk upright.
..人们可以仗义执言
No matter who he is or who she is.
不过他是谁，她是谁
He can walk upright and meet his friend or his enemy.
他可以挺起胸膛 去面对他的朋友和敌人
And he does not fear that because that enemy..
而他也不会因为得罪…
..may be in a position of great power..
..位居高位的权贵
..that he can be suddenly thrown in jail..
..而被突然间投入监狱
..to rot there without charges and with no recourse to justice.
..并在那烂到没有指控 和正义的援助
We have the Habeas CorpusAct and we respect it.
我们有人身保护法案 并且我们尊重这一法案
I began by saying that our history will be what we make it.
开始，我提到我们的历史 将由我们来构造
If we go on as we are,..
若我们继续这样下去…
..then history will take its revenge, and retribution will not limp..
..那么历史将会报复我们 而且这惩罚…
..in catching up with us.
将迅速降临我们身上
Just once in a while, let us exalt the importance of ideas and information.
偶尔地，让我们赞美一下 思想与见闻的价值
Let us dream to the extent of saying that on a given Sunday night..
让我们大胆梦想 将通常由“苏利文秀”（著名娱乐节目）
..the time normally occupied by Ed Sullivan..
..占据的周日晚间档
..is given over to a clinical survey on the state of American education.
..交给美国教育调查节目
And a weekor two later, the time normally used by Steve Allen..
然后一两周后 斯蒂夫 艾伦节目（娱乐节目）时间…
..is devoted to a thorough-going study of American policy in the Middle East.
..让给美国中东政策分析节目
Would the corporate image of their respective sponsors be damaged?
公司在赞助商眼中的形象 会受到伤害吗？
Would the shareholders rise up in their wrath and complain?
公司股东会 出离愤怒且抱怨吗？
Would anything happen..
除了几百万人在..
..other than a few million people would have received a little illumination..
..可能决定这个国家乃至这个公司..
..on subjects that may well determine the future of this country..
..未来的主题上受到点点启发..
..and therefore the future of the corporations?
…其他的，皆有可能会发生吗？
To those who say, "People wouldn't look, they wouldn't be interested,.."
对那些说道“观众不会看得 他们不感兴趣…”
"..they're too complacent, indifferent and insulated"..
“他们只要娱乐、且漠不关心 彼此绝缘”的人们
..I can only reply: there is, in one reporter's opinion,..
..我只能这样回答： “在一位记者眼中”..
..considerable evidence against that contention.
..“事实胜于雄辩”
But even if they are right, what have they got to lose?
可即使他们是对的 他们会失去什么？
Because if they are right,..
因为如果他们是对的
..and this instrument is good for nothing..
..且电视媒体一无是处
..but to entertain, amuse and insulate,..
..只是娱乐、消遣 和隔离我们的工具
..then the tube isflickering now..
..那么光管在闪烁
..and we will soon see that the whole struggle is lost.
..我们也将看到 所有的努力都将付诸东流
This instrument can teach.
电视可以教育公众
It can illuminate and it can even inspire.
它能引导 甚至是启发公众
But it can do so only to the extent that humans are determined to use it..
可只有人们坚定了 这样的目的去使用它
..towards those ends.
..电视才能实现它的价值
Otherwise, it is merely wires and lights..
否则，它只不过是 罩在盒子里的…
..in a box.
..电线和光管而已
Good night, and good luck.
祝您晚安，好运